Azazel.
Isaac.
What's up, guys?
What's going on?
It's Tuesday.
You know what that means, right?
It means only one thing.
The binding of Isaac.
That's right, we're playing Isaac.
Good ol' Isaac.
I love saying Isaac.
It brings me happiness.
What's going on, huh?
Man, you guys were going nuts for binding of Isaac.
The VOD on YouTube has like insane amounts of use.
I didn't expect this game to be that popular, but here we are.
I'm honestly very surprised about that.
I feel like Roblox aren't that popular to be seen, to be watching, you know?
It's not as fun to watch, I guess, but maybe that's just my stance on it?
Apparently not.
The stream was so good.
I'm glad you liked it.
I had a ton of fun as well.
It's a great symbiosis there.
Sarcoop, thank you for gifting two community subs, man.
I appreciated Sarcoop.
No, Sarcoopiff.
Sarcoopiff.
And WJT.
Eight months now.
Thank you.
GalaxyXile as well.
Subscribing with Prime, along with Toozie and Plantaro.
Is that two months?
What's up, Oliver?
What's up, Plantaro?
Jackson Two-Face, Liminal Roar.
I would have had way more than six months, but I missed a month somewhere.
Don't worry about it, man.
Don't worry about it.
Honestly, as long as people are watching, then that's more than enough.
Of course, I appreciate it when people subscribe, but as long as you're watching, that's more than enough.
Finally, I catch you live.
I'm going to try and stream a bit more in the future.
The last couple of months, I've been going through kind of a rough spot with my health.
But now I'm finally on top again, I think.
I've made some lifestyle changes and I'm trying to really stick to them this time.
And I think that's going to influence my streaming schedule as well.
We'll see.
Oliver, I'm making a blueprints parlor room compilation.
Go for it, man.
That sounds awesome.
Dude, I had so much fun with that.
That was so much fun.
When are you going to start streaming with a facecam when I'm at a million subscribers on YouTube?
Which will never happen.
But if it does happen, then I'm going to stream with a facecam.
I doubt it, though.
Maybe in 10 years.
Azazel is black for he is false.
What?
I don't know what that means.
That's a low bar.
Man, I've had this music stuck in my head since last stream.
Me too!
Dude, I've been going around my house whistling the soundtrack.
At that point, I knew I was fucked, you know?
I was standing there cooking, whistling the soundtrack.
It's such a good soundtrack to whistle as well.
It lends itself so well to whistling.
It's just such a memorable soundtrack.
First time watching Oliver, live, still watching the Minecraft series.
The first season, Quizzy?
Or the second season?
Nice to have you, though.
Hey, fresh doctor and no technology.
Thanks for the subs, man.
And the real XX Philae.
Good luck on winning, Oliver.
We believe in you.
Thank you.
You know what?
That's good, because I believe in myself as well.
Today is going to be different than last time, okay?
Last time, I was a little overwhelmed with everything, you know?
And I don't know, it was a little crazy, so I just sort of went with it.
Today, we're really going to dig down and try to frickin' nail this game.
I will do my utmost to achieve precision gaming status.
Holy shit, Lullaby.
I've never seen that effect before.
Just got here.
You want to enable mouse?
Wait, you can?
I didn't see it in the menu.
I even checked today.
There's no mouse option.
Am I absolutely blind?
Mouse controls are a kind of debug option.
Oh, no, then I... no, no, no, then I don't want to do it.
If it's not, like, officially, like, properly implemented, then no, no, no.
Then I don't want it.
That sounds too much.
I mean, I'm fine with the current controls.
The current controls are pretty good.
I actually kind of like them.
I don't really have an issue with it.
It's just that I've been so used to the mouse from playing Silksong, right?
I played the entirety of Silksong with just the mouse.
No keyboard.
Like, everything is happening on the mouse.
Every single bind.
So I just sit with one hand in my pocket and the other hand on my mouse.
That's how I play Silksong, you know?
So I was hoping I could do the same here, but that's not the case.
What was it in the pocket?
I'm just kidding, come on.
I'm one hand on the keyboard, another hand on the mouse.
Imagine that, though, just continuously scrolling the mouse left or right, or dragging it along the mouse pad, depending on which direction you want to go.
And if you don't continuously drag it, then you're going to stop moving.
Oh, no.
Why not get a facecam sooner?
I don't want to.
I'm going to be self-conscious about it being on camera.
I like sitting here in my underwear.
Oh, did I say that?
360 degree desk for that mouse.
I mean, yeah.
And then everything needs to be wireless then, wireless headphones and everything.
Living Yeet God.
First time chatter, Oliver, first time live watching.
The Binding of Isaac is easily my favorite game ever, and I love that you're playing it.
Love your content.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
A lot of people have been saying this.
People have, like, hundreds of hours in this game.
Which is still kind of crazy to me, but I think I may understand how now that I saw the list of items that you can get in this game.
By the way, I made some changes to the chat.
I noticed that the chat was overlapping a little bit with the UI last time, so I fixed that a little bit.
Hopefully it will function fine now.
There were also some minor bugs, but I made some adjustments, so it should be okay now.
Guys, I think it's time.
We're going to play some Isaac.
Are you ready?
I've got my water.
That's right.
No coke.
We're doing water today.
I'm staying clean.
We need to be level-headed and sharp for this game.
Oh, yeah.
I even ate freaking Greek yogurt this morning with nuts and sunflower seeds, blueberries.
That's right.
I even had some green fucking tea.
I never drink that.
That's right.
I am on the health wagon.
Which means I'm going to be playing much better.
You'll see.
I actually feel pretty good.
Okay, let's see here.
Switched over.
By the way, I had some crazy theories about Isaac and the story.
I'm going to share it later when I remember.
Right now, I just want to go.
Who am I?
Actually, who am I?
I unlocked a couple of people.
I unlocked this guy, Azazel.
Actually, I'm going to call him Azazel.
I hope you don't mind.
I kind of want to go back to Isaac for the first run.
Oh, that win streak?
Oh, why did it say minus?
It should be plus.
That's a bug.
I don't know what's happening there.
I definitely had five wins in a row last time.
But it happened right after I turned off the stream, though, so you missed it.
No, I'm going for... Ah, what should I do?
Let's take... Let's warm up with some Isaac.
Okay!
Here we are.
Let me get back into this.
Adjust the mousepad.
Rotate the keyboard at 32 degrees.
There we go.
Actually, that doesn't work here.
All right.
I'm nervous.
No mistakes today.
There we go.
We got these guys.
These are not dangerous at all.
Easy money.
We have to destroy all the poop, of course.
So let me think about this.
What is this door?
This door has spikes on the minimap.
It has blood on the entrance, but it's not going to damage me when I enter.
We got some money.
We got some money!
Wow, so lucky.
Let's go in here.
Okay, so obviously there's something going on here.
Yeah, and I guess I can just keep doing that.
It's like an exchange of health for maybe a random item.
It could also just be money.
I'm going to do it again.
Shit.
Okay, I'm taking this and then I'm leaving.
Anything else I can do in here?
Those look like bars up there, almost as if this is some kind of cell.
I'm not the first to have stepped in here.
Look at all this blood.
That's not my blood.
What do we have here?
Uh oh, we got poop!
I'm actually in trouble.
Kidding.
I'm totally killing it!
Oh no!
It's fine.
Don't panic.
I have trouble hitting things.
These little poops are kind of hard targets.
Small targets.
Okay, sweet.
I also have one bomb and one key right now.
I don't know if I should be destroying these pots.
Oh, I don't want to go in there though.
That's going to cost some HP.
Yeah, let's not do that.
Yeah, this way.
Okay, we got these guys.
They are going to shoot when I walk past them.
Nice.
Nice and clean.
Yeah, we got the bottom guy.
Wait, there we go.
Look at that.
Precision shooting.
Wow.
Maximum healing?
Shit, shit, shit.
Whoa.
Uh oh, uh oh.
Oh no.
Wow, this is a lot.
We got to bomb them.
It wasn't worth it.
That was not worth it.
I thought I could get them all or something.
One of them has two butts.
What the hell?
Or I guess it's just a standard but.
That's weird.
I got to play this safe.
Man, look at these precision shots coming in.
I need some upgrades to my damage and my everything, I guess.
I want to get upgrades.
Nice.
These guys are not that bad.
They're just chilling.
This is a big room though.
I did that pretty well, I'd say.
So wait, this is a shop.
It's open, it doesn't require a key.
This one was item right.
Backstabber.
Striking an enemy from behind deals double damage and applies a bleed effect.
Dealing additional damage over time based on its movement speed and leaving a trail of creep.
Okay.
So the faster they move, the more blood they're going to lose, I guess.
That's my assumption here.
The bottom three icons, I'm going to assume what that means.
This item can only be found in these crown rooms.
This, I don't even know, red cross room and question mark rooms.
Watch your back.
Now, if I go in here, that's going to say the exact same thing.
Okay.
Now there's a button.
Shit.
Actually, it's fine.
I can't even shoot.
I'm too far away.
Owned.
And if I click this, we get a bomb.
Interesting.
Wait, there's a rock here in the center now.
I'm going to try and destroy it.
Okay, that didn't do anything.
You also have light coming from above.
I wonder why that is.
Maybe just because this is a special room that has an item in it.
I got to be careful.
If I walk into things, I buy them.
This is some kind of treasure map.
Okay, so last time I did something here.
And I got money for it.
How did I do that?
Remember, I was standing right here.
Something happened.
Maybe there's like a secret on these walls.
Well, we got to destroy this.
Maybe now we can do it.
Okay.
Well, I'm saving my money.
Wait, I need to check something.
Oh, I was going to check whether or not I still had money saved up here, but I guess I do.
Why wouldn't it be saved, right?
Okay, here we go.
Green fly.
So what do you do?
Whoa.
It's just faster versions of the same flies as before.
Okay.
Two treasure chests.
Three keys.
Oh, nice.
This one.
Whoa.
That's a doll.
Mr. Dolly.
Range plus tears up.
Wow.
Why did that just appear?
Let's see here.
The tears and more range spawns three random heart pickups.
Ah, that makes sense.
Got it.
That's where that came from.
I thought maybe it meant that now that I cleared the room, so to speak, a.k.a.
I opened everything I could.
I did everything I could do in here.
Then some kind of reward popped up, right?
But no, that wasn't the case.
Oh, wow.
This guy needs to die.
He's going to shoot things at me.
Okay, good.
Nice.
Okay, that went pretty well.
Oh, the heart.
Maybe I shouldn't have taken that, actually, because that was a full heart.
That may have been a mistake.
Oh, you know what?
Let's go to that one room up here before we... No, no, no.
Let's kill this boss first, and then we decide.
Monstro.
All right, this is the guy that jumps, right?
I think it is, at least.
Also, I forgot whether or not I had this on hard or not.
I'm assuming it's going to save my setting.
From last time.
Okay, okay.
I'm not going too bad.
I'm going to jump.
There we go.
Whoa.
Yeah, easy.
Not bad.
Uh, roid rage, spun.
Speed and range up.
Whoa.
Wait, isn't that a crazy range?
Hold on.
Plus 2.5 range.
I think range is the one that is like a bow on the left.
So we have move speed.
Amount of projectiles.
Or maybe that's the speed, like the rate of fire.
Damage, range.
I don't know what the one is.
Luck, demon, and I don't even know, heaven.
Dude, I have so much HP.
What the hell?
What's actually happening?
No, I didn't mean to go in.
I meant to go back.
I fucked up.
Mama's watching TV and I'm some kind of semen?
Huh?
Or like a sperm?
What the fuck was that?
These movies are weird, man.
Ouch.
Did the little guy shoot like that?
This guy is trapped by poop.
That's just too bad, ain't it?
Can I maybe... Wait,
am I hitting him?
Oh my god, amazing shots.
Oh no, I freed the monster.
Okay, we got him.
And okay.
I'm gonna go in here.
So this is a red chest.
Apparently there's a difference between this and the other chests, right?
Pills.
Infested.
So I get allies.
That's the stuff you consume to, you know, empty your spine.
Or colon, I should say.
Do I go up here?
If I walk on that, I'm gonna get a coin, I guess.
Yeah, okay.
That's fine.
I do like a coin.
What is this room?
There's like nothing in here.
Guys, that is suspicious.
We're gonna bomb it.
Who is a god gamer?
Hell yeah.
What is this?
This guy's crying.
I'm not sure what's going on there.
Are we friends?
Wait, what is this room?
Okay, well, I feel like maybe that's not what I should have done.
Guys, watch this.
Oh, imagine, imagine though.
That would be crazy, wouldn't it?
Would actually be insane.
Oh, my attack speed is way higher.
Oh wow, I just took damage.
And then everyone died?
Somehow?
Go
in here.
What's that?
Bursting sac, spider love.
That doesn't sound nice.
Spider baby, one of three.
Many spider enemies become less dangerous.
Okay, and this one is only obtainable from crown rooms.
At least that's what I think.
Wow.
Oh no, I didn't mean to click that.
Oh well.
It is what it is.
Man, these guys have a lot of HP, huh?
Okay.
I think there's another secret in here.
Either north or south.
Wait a second.
Check this out.
There's light coming from the top.
Light race.
I only have one bomb though, that's the problem here.
Otherwise, I would have bombed this and then bombed the... Oh, there's also a little fly symbol on the wall up there.
It's like a little loose brick.
I don't want to waste my bomb.
There's a blue guy here.
Whoa!
Wait, so when I take damage, they all die?
Is that a thing I have?
I don't understand.
Why is this happening?
Isn't that weird?
And then the fire is turned on.
Oh, you know what I think it is?
I think it's... I had hearts, didn't I?
I had black hearts.
Maybe that's what happens when you lose a black heart.
Then everyone in the room dies.
Yeah, that has to be it.
Okay, that's pretty cool.
Assuming I'm correct on that.
A big room up here?
Whoa, okay, we got a boss there.
Oh, no, I kind of want to walk in there.
No, I don't.
There's nothing for me in there.
I don't need batteries right now.
This room is utterly suspicious.
Right?
Like, that's weird.
Also, I'm 100% demon mode right now, whatever that means.
Wait, there's a fly here.
A black fly.
Like this item to it.
Oh, we're at 53 in the donation.
Try this again.
What did I do here last time?
I destroyed something on the shelves.
And then money came out.
How did I do that?
It's this.
It's a tarot card that we have not identified.
Now you find what you desire.
Oh, that sounds good.
We can read about that.
No, we can't.
It's question marked.
So I guess we try it.
Okay,
so that takes us to the crown room.
I guess I do desire the crown.
I want to rule over everyone.
Isaac shall become king.
Oh, how dare you poop.
There we go.
Oh, little mini Isaac's.
They're crying blood.
That's messed up.
That guy's gonna explode.
Whoa, check this out.
Oh my god, there's three treasure chests.
No, dude, I wish I was a sasyl right now.
I could have flown across all of this.
Man, wait, if I blow this up, I have another bomb.
Is the explosion going to reach though?
Let's check.
Oh, not.
No, barely not.
Okay, that's fine.
Now we know that at least.
Have you missed some bombs somewhere?
I mean, there's a bomb embedded in the rock here, but how do I... Yo, what if I can pick up the rocks at some point?
Like last time?
I can seize up the bomb and that's how I get the bomb.
Or maybe I throw the rock with the bomb embedded in it and it's like a bigger bomb.
I can see both things being a thing here.
Okay, let's do this.
Kirklings.
What the fuck is this?
Whoa.
One of them is down.
That's not too bad.
Wait, I'm taking damage.
What's happening?
Oh, maybe I can't walk on certain surfaces?
Something just happened and I lost demon and I gained heaven.
Huh?
Blue cap.
Hold on.
Fun guy.
More tears.
Okay, so more tears means attack speed because we got 0.85.
Wait, what is shot speed then?
No, no, no.
Now I'm confused.
Oh, that is shot speed.
Oh, it's the speed of the projectile, I guess.
Plus one health, heals one red heart.
Okay, that's totally worth though, having four health.
It's crazy.
Wait, what is... What the hell is this here?
Oh,
it's this... Okay, it's this place.
So now I can give up a health to gain one of these things.
What do I want?
Do I want the demon star or the... Obviously, I don't know.
Some kind of nice necklace.
I'm gonna go for the demon mode.
Pentagram, damage up!
And we gained demon and lost heaven.
Okay.
Wait, I can take another one.
Dude, should I take another one?
Guppy's color, eternal life.
Wait, what do you mean eternal life?
50% chance to be revived with half heart when taking lethal damage.
Okay, that is actually kind of sick.
This was worth it.
Absolutely worth.
Absolutely.
Here we go.
Level three.
We got poop as a present.
Jokes on them, I love poop.
Uh oh.
Kill him!
Ah, I'm stuck in the corner!
That was bad.
I put myself in that situation.
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
This one!
If I take this and stay alive until the end, I get extra heart.
Right?
So I'm not gonna take this.
We're gonna wait with this until later.
I'm gonna play this so incredibly smart.
Come here, guys.
I need to die.
Okay.
Okay, so this door, this is a real mystery.
Last time, I thought it was because we needed to clear every room.
And maybe I'm right on that.
But I think if that's the case, it also includes all these really hidden rooms, you know, where you have to destroy a wall.
We're gonna have to test that today.
Also, I look absolutely ridiculous.
With the demon horns, the tears running down our eyes, the little doll at our side and the bib we're wearing.
Bro, this is a ridiculous outfit.
This is the opposite of demon mode.
Come on.
Whoa, I hate that!
Absolutely disgusting enemy.
Oh, it's bleeding because I hit it in the back.
Backstabber.
That's me.
Oh, I needed that.
Thank you.
I was about to say I'm low on HP here.
What is this little mushroom?
We got blue guys.
He's down.
No!
I got hit.
Unbelievable.
This is getting hairy.
I'm in big trouble.
Just kill him.
Man, I'm having real trouble hitting these little guys here.
It's tough.
Oh, this is good.
This is good though.
What's that?
Cursed eye.
Cursed charge shot.
Charge shot that fires up to five tears in a burst.
Taking damage mid charge teleports Isaac to a random room?
What?
That is a crazy item.
Wow.
Okay.
Sure.
Oh man, I'm so low HP.
This is... I may have to go get this hard up here guys.
Otherwise it's over.
Nah, just go.
Oh my god.
This is insane.
Okay, we killed one.
This guy in the center also does damage.
Oh my god.
Man,
I shouldn't have taken those two.
I don't even know.
I exchanged my health for the items.
I got greedy.
But this was a good warm up.
This was a good warm up.
Now's the real deal Bob.
Here we go Bob.
You ready Bob?
I don't know why I'm calling you Bob now, but your name is Bob.
Wait, why does this look like this?
Huh?
Isaac, what the fuck is this?
I'm confused.
We have wooden boards and wooden panels.
This is like a cabin.
This is not a basement.
Kill him.
It's not too bad actually.
We got him.
Pill.
Tears down.
No.
That's absolutely disgusting.
I don't like that.
I could try to bomb a random wall here.
Should we gamble?
No, no, let's not be dumb.
Let's wait.
Let's go here.
The music is different too.
What is even happening right now?
Shit,
shit.
Oh wait, we gotta destroy this poop first.
And then yeah, that's how we do it.
Plate safe.
Plate slow.
They're so fast.
Oh my god.
There's five smaller ones.
Dude, this is horrible.
Okay, nice, nice.
Oh man, I nailed that.
Oh, gamer.
Very nice.
Cool music.
I'm not gonna enter here because I don't have any money anyway.
Actually, let's just have a look.
Maybe we can do this trick again here.
I don't understand what I did.
BFF and a card.
Wait.
Oh, I accidentally turned this off.
Okay.
Wait.
Money for me?
Okay, we got spiders and a big dude.
The big dude is not dangerous at all.
He's totally chilling.
We can fart all he wants.
Oh god, I hate spiders.
Wow, wow.
They jump over rocks.
That was a good shot there.
I'm proud of myself.
I don't understand why all the levels look like this all of a sudden.
Wait, there's actually a room we missed up here.
Oh, okay.
Hey, look at this.
We missed a room here.
Meat glasses?
X-ray vision.
I've seen everything.
Oh, there's a hole here.
Can we just enter or do we need a bomb though?
Let's see if there's any other things it does.
Reveals and opens secret room entrances.
Okay, so it's not just an illusion.
Very cool.
There's something about this rock though.
The one I can't sort of budge.
You can't blow it up, apparently.
Maybe you need two bombs.
I haven't tried that yet.
Okay, so what is this here?
Another hole here.
Oh, we take a key.
The Empress for the current room plus 1.5 damage and more speed.
Okay, so I should really be saving this, right?
This is like a trump card, so to speak.
Yeah.
What is it with these weird sort of statues here of Isaac?
Sometimes they're also hanging from the ceiling.
Wait, what is this?
Oh!
Oh, wait a minute!
There was like a guy in there, sort of mini-boss, right?
That's what that icon on the map means.
A mini-boss.
There's also a room down here we didn't go to.
I kind of want to go in there.
We have a heart here we can pick up, so I think we're fine.
I'm stepping on it.
Thanks.
Then I can grab some more HP.
I have a feeling more will happen if I keep stepping on it, you know?
There's probably multiple thresholds.
We've got to be careful here now.
Okay, they only go right around.
Wait, what's with this rock here?
This rock looks different.
Hold on.
I'm gonna blow it up.
Oh, look at that!
Look at me go!
Get up!
Oh, yeah, I was close!
Wait, I gotta be on the lookout for stuff like that.
I have three monies now.
Should I be using it?
I could buy this one, except I can't, apparently?
Why is it red?
I'm buying it.
So I can buy it.
Copies the effect of Isaac's active item.
Huh?
Oh, I don't have an active item.
Reveals the map.
Oh, I kind of want that instead.
Ah, but here's what we're gonna do.
We are going to enter the boss.
We're gonna activate the Empress, kill the boss, come back here, grab this card, and move to the next floor.
Right?
This is the plan.
Oh, look at this!
Another secret revealed!
Lots of battery.
Is that Super Meat Boy?
Look at that!
That's totally like a... look at that easter egg.
That's amazing!
Um, I can't do anything with these batteries, though.
Maybe if I put the batteries next to the posters, then, uh, I don't know, someone named Sully will appear.
I'm totally pulling this out of my ass.
Imagine if I actually stumble on something here.
Okay, whatever.
Move on.
Time to activate the Empress.
The Duke of Flies.
Wait, uh... Bro, there's no way I can read that in time!
That looked super interesting!
They need to fix that.
That is such an oversight.
Okay, so I apparently became a demon with the Empress.
Something huge just happened, as well, that I didn't get to read.
Wait, maybe something happened in here that I can read about?
No, not really.
Wow.
Killed the little flies.
This guy's not too hard, actually.
We're totally chilling here.
Careful here.
Okay, so check it out.
I'm not gonna pick up the... What's that?
Rotten meat.
HP up?
Really?
That brings my HP up.
Plus one health.
Oh!
Sick!
Okay, that's huge.
Uh, I'm not gonna leave yet.
We have things to do.
I'm going to go in, uh, here.
Then I'm gonna grab this guy.
The world.
What is this one over here?
Can I read about it before I... No, it's a question mark.
But I wonder if it's the same as this one, because the pattern is the same.
Oh, I don't have any money anyway.
I can't buy it.
Whoa.
Let's look for more of those rocks!
Uh,
wait, wait, wait.
What else can I do?
Let's go in this room and waste some more HP, because we have healing in the last room.
That didn't do anything?
You feel blessed?
Okay.
What does that mean?
Uh, I don't think I'm gonna do it again.
No, I'm going.
I feel blessed, apparently.
I hope that's a good thing.
Oh, this guy's coming the other way!
What the hell?
That's not how it's supposed to work!
Oh, God.
This way.
It changed direction on me.
Okay, now we go down to the boss.
What was this?
Oh, yeah, batteries.
I have six bombs.
Whoa.
Let's go!
Let's go, man!
Oh, that was only the first level?
I thought I was on, like, third.
Jesus Christ.
Let's keep it going, huh?
Cellar two.
Okay.
Wait, no, no, no, no.
The spiders are definitely scarier than anything else.
But the poop is also quite dangerous.
Got him.
I don't know if I should be holding down the attack key or sort of really carefully attacking, you know, shot per shot here.
Oh, that's nice.
Okay.
I could go in there, but I'm not going to.
I'm scared.
Uh-oh.
This guy's red.
What does that mean?
Probably nothing good.
It's an especially potent fart, I guess.
What if there's, like, a secret where you want to let him fart on you and it actually buffs you?
That'll be funny.
Um, let's go left.
Oh, wait, this is just happening all the time?
Yo, the x-ray vision is insanely good.
I thought it was just, like, for that one level.
That's crazy.
Okay, we got some buttons in here.
Oh.
Okay.
But I can't reach them, unfortunately.
Dude, look at all these secrets!
What the frick?
Thanks.
Someone is hanging here.
What does that mean?
So a lot of rooms have this in common, where someone is either hanging here or they're just sitting there.
I like these blue fireflies.
That's kind of neat.
Oh, this is a shop.
I don't have any money.
Placebo.
Oh, yeah, I had that last time.
I don't want it now.
Let's go in here.
Gotta cry, but, wow, what the fuck did Jamba lot?
Holy shit!
That's a wild enemy.
Absolutely out of control.
I am so scared of those now.
There's more.
Just anticipate the jump.
Yeah, I didn't anticipate the jump.
I had one job.
I didn't do it.
Are they spawning little spiders?
They are.
It's horrible.
Oh, no, it's the one of those.
He's going to spawn smaller ones.
Oh, my God.
I can't handle spiders.
It's too much.
Oh.
Okay, kill him quick before he spawns more.
Oh, oh, Jesus Christ.
Nice.
Definitely going to go in here.
That is some kind of party hat with runes on it.
The wiz.
Double wizshot.
What is that?
Isaac fires two tears at once, but at split diagonal angles.
Oh, no, that doesn't sound good.
Spectral tears?
That sounds horrible.
Oh, the spectral means it goes through objects?
Wait.
Oh, okay, okay.
Maybe it's good, then.
This is a real trade-off, isn't it?
I'm going to go back and collect some HP.
I've got to play this one safe here.
Now we can grab that one and also this one in here.
Nice.
Let's go here and then down.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, this is going to be so awkward, though.
Oh, but look at this.
I hit both.
Oh, that's dope.
Oh, I'm going to have to get used to this.
Wow.
Oh, no, we got little spider bros.
Okay, let's go over here.
Look at me with the glasses and the party hat.
We're having a party here.
Whoa.
Am I saving the sender?
I think I may be.
See ya.
Oh, God.
Oh, no.
Wow.
Jesus.
Kill them.
They keep spawning.
We got to kill them fast.
It's impossible to aim.
Okay, we're dealing some damage here.
Wow.
Jesus.
How am
I alive?
Too many spiders.
Okay, fuck it.
We're going in.
Bombs.
Kill them.
Absolutely not.
Wow.
That was crazy.
And then we have a boss.
Wait, there's a room here.
Whoa.
I'm in a chapel.
Wait, if I pick that up, am I...?
Question mark.
What does this mean?
This way.
I guess I'm just going to go to the boss.
There's actually two rooms I'm missing.
Let's go to the boss.
No, go back and then boss.
Yeah.
I like the fact that those things pop out spikes only like a second after you enter.
Because you don't know where they're going to be when you enter, so that's a nice, you know, feature.
Okay.
Oh, I could enter here.
This way first.
Okay, another empty room?
Watch.
Ah, wait, I'm an idiot.
It's going to be revealed, isn't it?
Okay, that was a bad moment.
Never mind that.
I didn't see it.
What's this?
It's like a library.
Joker, teleport to the devil or angel room.
Angel room?
Is that what those symbols on the left are?
Devil and angel?
Number six, the lovers, spawns two red hearts.
Oh, that's actually pretty good, I guess.
I guess this, the world, is useless to me because I have these glasses.
Also, what's this?
Book of shadows?
Bookworm, zero of three.
Gain a damage nullifying shield for ten seconds.
This is an active.
Yeah, and that's the one I use with space.
Got it.
Okay, so this...
um...
teleport to the devil or... I kind of want that.
I want to go to the angel room.
Unless that is what I was in just before, the chapel.
Maybe that was the angel room.
The demon room is probably the one where there was the giant demon statue, right?
Gotta be.
Oh, God.
Oh!
Can I cross?
Kill him.
What's this?
Blood oath, bleed me dry.
That sounds cool.
Stabs Isaac at the start of each floor, depleting as many red hearts as it can without killing him?
What?!
The stab grants bonus damage and speed for the rest of the floor.
The more health sacrificed to this effect, the more stats it will provide.
Oh, no!
Okay, we're grabbing the card with the extra hearts.
Also, I'm going to use the Joker now.
Go.
I used the wrong item!
Fuck me, dude.
Oh, I guess we're here.
Wait, where...
I don't even see where we are on the map, though.
So, what's this?
Collect this.
This one was 50% chance to be revived with half a heart.
That has never worked for me.
I feel like I always die with this.
But I could get it.
I think I'm going to get this one, because I haven't had it before.
Dark matter.
Damage up plus fear shot?
Oh, that sounds good.
Some damage.
Chance for tears to apply fear effect.
Chance increases with luck.
Okay.
Hero luck, though.
And what is this one?
Dude, should I sacrifice another heart?
I'm addicted to doing it!
I want to sacrifice a heart!
I don't know.
Should I?
Also?
My x-ray glasses are gone.
I guess they have been replaced with these now.
It's kind of messed up.
I'm going to take it.
Little brimstone.
Evil friend.
Conjoined.
Following familiar that charges and fires a brimstone beam attack.
Okay.
You better be good.
Oh, no, I...
Oh, it's like a mini-asazel!
Haha, that's cool!
How come I can't destroy fires?
Something's going on here.
Wait, how come this room wasn't revealed with my x-ray glasses?
Okay, what I... Oh, I also forgot.
Wait, oh wait, what?
Oh, so he charges the more I hold it!
Ah!
And he's going to shoot in the direction...
Ah, okay, okay, I see, I see.
That's kind of dope.
This is not good, though.
I have no HP now.
This is bad.
But here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to go back here and grab the other card.
That's going to spawn hearts for me.
Actually, let me do this here.
So it's cube.
Okay,
it's not even going to reveal the room I was just in on the map.
The lovers.
So I'm going to use this when I get to a new level, I guess.
Also, hold on.
These walls look hella suspicious, but I guess there's nothing there since I have x-ray vision.
Okay.
Wait, how come my shots are black?
What is happening here again?
Is it that one?
A chance for tears to apply fear effect.
Okay, it's probably that one, then.
That's doing it.
I kind of regret losing two hearts here.
This is not great.
I'm so low on HP, you know, like, okay, I get more items, but I'm probably going to die now because of it.
Ah!
Wow, that was close, man!
Let's go, let's go.
Fuck it.
It's time for the haunt.
Never seen that before.
Weirdly fitting.
Okay, so they turn...
Oh, that's weird.
They turn invisible half the time.
They're not taking any damage.
Okay, I killed one of the small ones.
I could use the little guy actually to aim like this.
Yeah, okay, okay, now he's... now he's damageable.
Got it.
Okay.
Sick.
So far, so good.
Whoa, he also does that one, huh?
Oh, cool!
Stuy?
Damage plus rain shot?
Ew, it's looking like some kind of chicken effect.
Full chicken.
Increases damage by 28%.
What a arbitrary amount.
Plus 6.5 range.
The buffs from this item apply only to shots fired from the right eye.
I don't understand this mechanic with the left and right eye.
Not yet.
Yeah.
Okay.
I will be grabbing this and that.
And there's this weird rock again.
Maybe I can use this laser.
No.
Okay, so I'm going to be losing HP now, right?
If I understand correctly.
This is not going to be good.
Uh, Isaac, did you just poop in the middle of nowhere?
Like a little poop just fell out?
I only have a blue heart?
Okay, thank God I grabbed this thing.
The lovers.
Wow.
So I'm going to get a buff now though, right?
At least?
Man, I have such low attack speed.
It's horrible.
Does not feel good.
Oh, wait, I just... Wait, how do I do that?
Hold on.
Oh, I can sort of... If I accidentally shoot right, I can change it to up.
If I need to later.
Like right now I can go like this.
Sick.
Okay.
Got a key.
Let's see what's in here.
Get him.
Wow.
Ah!
Fucking bullet hell!
This is crazy!
Wow.
I'm so bad at that stuff.
Okay, so this one is open for some reason now.
Why is that?
Is it because we are at 100% demon?
It's definitely nothing to do with the amount of rooms cleared.
We know that now.
It's just sort of open now for some reason.
The Empress.
Mayor Rage Spring Power.
Nice.
Man, the diagonal shots are hella awkward.
Like, it's not good.
I don't like it that much.
It's really hard to get used to.
But I guess it does mean we're shooting two shots at a time, which is...
I mean, theoretically better, right?
If you can master it?
Tomatoes?
Oh no, they're red.
But they're charging up or something.
Oh, and I got hit again.
That's fine, that's fine.
So I'm assuming there's no secrets here because my x-ray glasses are not doing any reveals for me.
Oh my god!
I
hate those things!
Oh, nice.
Monies.
Okay, so we're entering a big room now.
This is so exciting!
I have no HP though.
Maybe a bad idea!
I'm gonna die!
It's over.
They all died?
How come they all died?
There's a black shit in the center!
What does that mean?
I'm scared of that.
I can't get over there, unfortunately.
I need hearts.
Ooh, I could... Oh, there's a secret here.
I could gamble and maybe get some healing.
Crap.
A pill.
Ay, nice!
Hell yeah!
Again!
Oh no!
Oh well, still worth, I think.
Let's check out the secret.
Oh, that's ten!
No, it's five, okay.
Still good though.
So look at this, there's three in here now.
Two of them are hanged.
This guy's just sitting there.
What is the meaning of this?
He has a little black fly next to him.
I wonder if I come here with a black fly, maybe I can somehow do something.
I'm not sure what that is supposed to mean.
I'll come back.
I'll never come back.
Oh god.
Oh, these guys are not that bad, actually.
They have the same attack I have!
They're stock shooting diagonal too!
No, that wasn't gonna hit anything.
I have this little mini Azazel though.
He can do that.
That's something you can't do, huh?
Oh god.
I also gotta abuse the fact that I can shoot through obstacles.
I haven't really done that yet.
I can abuse that, you know?
Like, if I just stand behind here, I should be safe, I guess.
I really should be utilizing that more.
Okay, here's the boss.
I'm not going in there.
Not yet.
Oh god, this guy up there.
How am I gonna deal with you, huh?
Jesus.
This is insanely difficult for me.
Why didn't that hit him?
Fucking die!
Good.
Please die.
Oh, thank god!
Oh!
I gotta get in here and get that heart.
I need to.
I could go in there.
That requires a key though.
I don't have that much money, so I'm not gonna do it yet.
Not yet.
Wait, there's a room over here.
Up here, according to the map.
Hey!
Oh, is this place again?
Uh, oh, this is the one that does the thing.
I forgot whether or not I had to kill the boss with it, or...
Um, I'm coming back.
Coming back for that.
Yeah, not yet.
Also, why am I glowing red all of a sudden?
Is that something I picked up?
I'm not sure.
Also, let's not forget we have the Empress.
And that one did what?
More damage.
Okay, it's just more damage.
And that is with Q, not space, not space.
Also, what was my space thing?
Painted damage, nullifying shield...
Oh, oh, holy shit!
I should be using that!
What the fuck?
Wait, does that mean I can put it on now and go through that door?
I don't know if I should try it.
Let's not experiment with that.
That sounds like a bad idea.
A golden key!
Oh, wait, we got enemies.
I almost didn't see them.
I can't get it, no!
I don't know how to get that.
Shield me!
I need it, I need it!
Just hide behind rocks!
Hide behind the rocks.
Oh yeah, my tactic is superb.
My style is immaculate.
Wonderful!
And battery, nice!
I can't get in there though, that's unfortunate.
I'm gonna save my special shield for the boss.
What's that?
Seraphine, sworn friend.
Another follower, conjoined.
Two out of three!
What happens when we get to three out of three?
Following familiar that fires slow homing tears.
And that was it here.
There's one big elongated room over here.
I'm also gonna destroy this poop.
Oh my goodness!
Wow.
I just have projectiles everywhere.
Look at my little army of followers!
That is amazing.
I have three followers right now.
Okay, go in here.
These guys are gonna explode.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Whoa.
Okay.
Oh no.
No, that's not worth it for a coin.
Fuck that.
Absolutely not.
Oh, I keyed.
Sweet.
What is this room up here though?
Oh!
Yo, I'm gonna try this.
You ready?
Oh, it works!
Oh no!
There's spiders!
No!
This was not worth it.
I've made a gruesome mistake.
I think.
Not good.
I'm at 1 HP.
Let's go to the shop room.
I wanna see what I can buy.
I have some money.
Oh man, I was hoping for some health.
I mean, we do have a bag here we can buy.
Oh no.
It was not good.
I'm in deep shit.
Heal me!
Okay, well.
Thanks.
Uh...
Oh wait, we had this?
Just put it on.
We need it.
We need it!
Wish me luck against the peep!
Oh, he looks happy to see me.
Please be easy.
Oh, he's shooting green things at me.
He's gonna jump, okay.
Got it.
It's not too bad so far.
We're chilling.
He's spawning a little guy.
Can I even damage that guy?
Oh god.
Oh, that was close.
Holy...
Come on, keep dealing damage.
Wow.
Dodge it!
Come on!
Get him!
Die and lock the catacombs!
HP me!
Roit rage, speed and range up.
Nice.
Wait, don't I have one of those already?
No, that was from the last one, I guess.
Okay.
We made it.
And there's a room here.
Oh no, I'm not doing that.
Absolutely not.
Although that one on the right looks insane.
Don't do it, don't do it, you idiot.
We're not gonna do it.
We're not doing it.
Nope.
Let's go.
Level four.
Mom shows us no love, it seems.
Caves two.
Oh, whoa!
Wait, the door opened just now!
Shit.
Uh oh.
I'm in danger.
What a...
Run!
There's no way I can run from those!
It's okay, it's okay.
That was a funny run.
I had a lot of fun with that one, though.
That was good.
Kinda wanna try another character.
Hold on, let me also just quickly move this over.
There we go.
What is this challenge?
Pitch black.
Eye, brow, pet trauma.
When life gives you...
That's nice.
Nah, new run.
I wanna try...
Should we try the new one?
We can do this one.
Lazarus.
Let's try it.
Oh, that's a demon right there.
That's a demon.
Oh, nice haircut.
Beautiful haircut there.
So wait, we have the times one up there.
Wait, we have a pill?
Range up.
Nice!
So we just start with a pillow?
What?
Is this a library?
I don't have a key, though.
Man, you shoot normally.
Got it.
Okay, okay, here we go.
Maybe kill the small ones here, actually.
Man, they have a lot of HP, huh?
Okay.
No money's for me.
There's also something about these pots here.
I can definitely do something with.
Let's go down here.
Is that a toenail?
It's a finger.
Watch where you point that.
Oh, I can actually point it.
What does that do?
Familiar that points in whichever direction Isaac is facing, and deals damage to all enemies in its direct line of sight.
Wow.
Just by being pointed at?
Can I laugh at people, too, now?
Laughing and pointing?
I gotta see this.
Or is it only when they touch?
I don't see people...
Oh, they are taking damage.
I saw them flash red for a second there.
It doesn't seem that good.
Kill the little guys.
Wait, so if I just stand like this...
Ah, it hit me.
I don't like the finger.
It's defaulting back to looking up or down, I mean.
I wish I could just sort of place my character to the right or left, and he would stay there.
That's not the case.
Oh, man.
Oh, the little ones are gonna shoot, yeah.
I think I'm gonna die here, guys.
An early one.
Oh, he explodes when he dies, okay.
Maybe it's all the black ones.
They explode when they die.
I'm actually gonna go in here.
Fuck it.
I'm gonna fight him straight up.
Oh, right.
You're fast.
You're a fast boy.
Ow!
Jesus.
Wow.
Okay.
Now we run.
It's not that bad, actually.
Just gonna start running any second now.
Oh, wow, the big one's down.
I've never had this happen before.
Oh, he's angry now.
Oh!
Wow, he cut me off!
I'm gonna die.
Jesus.
Magic scab.
H-plea- oh, ew.
That ain't good.
Plus one luck, plus one health, heals one red- Oh, wow, that sounds really good, actually.
Wait, it says plus one luck, but we had- We're at zero luck now.
Does that mean we were at minus one luck before?
Maybe that's just this guy's deal, you know?
He's just unlucky.
By default.
Maybe that's the thing.
No money.
Look at this little doll hanging.
Hey!
Yeah, I can't use it for anything.
Let's go this way.
I have one key I can use to get into the library.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, look at this one.
Monster manual, temporary buddy generator?
It's an active item.
Someone's a random familiar that lasts for the rest of the floor.
Okay, so the entire stage right now.
Bookworm one of three.
This one was temporary invisibility.
Right.
No, wait, what?
Why is it called Book of Shadows?
Oh, that's just the name, I guess.
It was a bookworm, two out of three.
We've got to find another book.
I want to see what that does.
I like this one, though.
Damage nullifying shield.
It's not just going to make me invulnerable for ten seconds, right?
I'm assuming it's just one hit.
Otherwise, that would be super broken.
But I kind of like this.
I want to try this one.
Actually, no, no, no.
Wrap this.
Go down here.
Put it on.
Boink.
Oh, shit.
Oh, my God, the little asshole spiders!
They're so hard to see.
Hate spiders.
The worst enemies in the game.
Can I get a bomb for it?
Yikes.
Oh, I got to go back through here.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Now, the question is, when I pick this up, will I get full mana?
I will.
Okay, cool.
Sweet.
Good to know that.
I don't know if I should put it on right now.
I guess it would be kind of a waste.
Then again, we are low on HP and there's a boss coming up.
Ah, it's one of the early bosses, right?
Oh, wait, we killed him?
Oh, we killed the boss already, oh.
Well, there you go.
I forgot.
Why is there a timer on the next floor?
Okay, let's go fast.
We're going mega fast.
Speed, speed.
Neon, neon.
Let's go.
Okay, there's nothing in here.
Uh, rip.
We keep, we leave.
Go, go, go.
Press the...
Oh, no.
Wow!
Unfair, unfair.
Oh, this one!
Nevermind.
It looked special.
I was imagining it, apparently.
Monster manual.
No!
Wait, I'm back.
Huh?
Maybe that's his stick, you know?
You come back?
Alright, speed, speed.
Go fast.
Kill him.
They all explode.
I'm in trouble.
This is really bad.
Wow.
Health.
Gimme.
We're going fast.
I don't know why, but we're going fast.
Uh, there's a bomb over here.
Kill this guy.
What?
Oh, is that my friend?
What's that?
Box of spiders?
It's a box of spiders.
Spider, baby.
Spawns photo, eight blue spiders.
Uh, okay, I guess I like that.
That's cool.
Keep going.
Spawn him.
Oh my god, oh my god!
I'm not going to be able to tell who's friend or foe.
Uh, this way.
Uh, kill all the spiders.
Get him, spiders!
Come on!
Good.
Oh, that was close.
Up, up, up.
Get him, get him, get him.
More spiders!
Good, good, good, good, good.
Wonderful.
Oh yeah.
Wow.
I need HP.
Boss?
We're going!
The Duke of Flies!
Wow, he just frickin' died!
Consolation prize, plus one to lowest...
Does that mean I failed whatever was going on here with the timing?
I have a feeling that's what that was.
On pickup grants a stat increase based on whichever one is the lowest relative to the others.
On pickup drops one pickup that Isaac has the least of.
Okay, so I guess I got the heart.
Uh, okay, okay.
I'm gonna move on.
Just go.
Why am I a little...
I don't know.
Sperm thingy in that video.
I don't understand that.
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
The Duchess!
God, gamer!
Unbelievable gaming.
Right, happening right...
Oh, this guy's gonna shoot things?
He can only shoot down.
Don't you...
Me.
I will...
You.
Oh, he wants bombs?
We can give him bombs.
Eat.
You asshole.
Wow, that was a waste.
Can't believe it.
I don't understand what is happening here.
Why am I somehow dealing area of effect damage?
How is this working?
Oh, is it the...
Maybe it's just the finger hitting these poops.
Yeah.
It's gotta be...
Oh, God!
Ow!
Dude, this is crazy.
I'm gonna die here.
Come on, wake up!
Oh, my God.
Wait, there's a heart over here somehow.
Are you gonna shoot?
Oh, you're still shooting.
Oh, no.
Oh, I'm gonna get it.
I can't!
I don't have a bomb!
No!
Crap!
Come on.
Finger, do your thing.
Finger them!
Nice.
Nothing for me, huh?
That's too bad.
Go up here and then left.
No, in here.
Oh!
I'm buying that.
Totally buying that.
That was huge.
What is this thing?
Like, some kind of inhaler.
I had that last time.
Night light.
Creates a cone of light in front of Isaac.
Oh, that's a good one, too.
I really like that.
That's gonna synergize well with the finger, actually.
Can you think about it?
These guys are gonna explode?
Oh, no way!
No way that just happened.
I found a secret room!
Insanity.
Huh?
Oh, wait.
I can't do this.
Whoa!
Huh?
Dude, if I pick one of these up, I die, I think.
I can't pick them up.
Oh, no.
I'm in such deep trouble.
I don't know where to go.
This way.
I think it's over for me.
Oh, god.
These guys don't shoot anything, right?
No, no!
Money?
Oh, my god, I'm rich?
What's that?
Mom's eyeshadow.
Okay.
Yes, mother.
That's one of three.
Chance to fire charging charming tears.
Chance increases with luck.
Charming tears?
Oh, it's going to make them turn to my side, I guess.
Uh-oh.
Whoa!
Ooh!
Spiky stones!
I can't get over there.
I guess some rooms are just not possible for certain characters.
Oh, get them.
Wow.
Don't give me that heart.
No, I need it.
Oh, I can get it.
I thought I couldn't access.
I'm so happy right now.
Okay, we got a jumping jack.
He's charmed.
It's boss time.
Also, what was this brick?
Oh, it was a box of spiders.
Right.
Let's use that now.
Against Gertie Jr. Okay, I do remember the boss, but I don't remember the boss.
You know what I mean?
Wow.
Wait, that's new.
You didn't used to do that.
Charmed!
Oh my God.
Somehow I'm back.
I'm back.
I got a somehow second chance at life.
I don't understand why.
Damage.
Oh, plus HP up is huge.
I needed that so bad right now.
Dude, I'm going to be greedy.
I'm going back.
I'm going back, baby.
That's right.
You heard me.
We're going back.
There's things to do.
I'm going to go in here.
Gimme.
Oh, okay.
Okay, so it's half a heart you lose when you enter.
I thought it was a full heart.
That's actually great news.
I can get this now.
I'm an idiot.
Why didn't I get the other heart?
Shit!
Ah, well, it happens.
I'm kind of rich.
I want to go buy things.
Let's check it out.
Ah, I don't have enough for this.
Too bad.
I was 15 for the nightlight.
I could go in here, but yeah, let's do it.
No money?
Oh my God, I feel cheated.
That is unreal.
I was hoping for money.
Wait, there's some money bags up here, it seems.
Ah, I can't reach it, though.
That's too bad.
There's another heart in here I can grab.
Oish, that was close.
Next level, next level.
This guy...
Oh, it makes sense.
His name is Lazarus.
Came back from the dead, right?
And it looks like it resets every time you...
go to a new stage, because now I have X1 up there.
That's actually kind of cool, I like this.
There's a pill I want, but I can't get it.
Oh no.
I see.
Where's the other button?
Oh, I see it.
Oh my God.
I'm terrible.
That's okay.
Oh, these red ones are... these charms!
I like the charm one.
The charm one is great.
A jawbreaker.
Don't chew on it.
In Danish we call that a hölkivbodge.
Which means, shut up, Candy.
Because you put it in the mouth of a child and they shut up, you know?
Oh, it's in the bottom.
10% chance to fire a tooth shot.
Chance increases with luck.
Okay.
Get him.
Yeah!
Dude,
I want to charm one of these flies so bad.
Is that just me?
What even are these things supposed to be, like little floppyjacks?
Oh, he was jumping.
That was a crazy jump.
More like jumpingjacks.
Wow, this guy's crazy like a boss.
What?
That is the craziest enemy of all time.
Unbelievable.
It's over.
How am I going to kill that guy?
That's impossible.
That is impossible.
I can't win.
Okay, here's the plan.
If I shoot him, he's not going to pop, right?
We're just going to push him along.
There.
Wake up.
You're not...
Okay, here we go.
Oh.
Wake up, son.
How dare you?
Okay, okay, we made it.
Almost.
Push him.
There we go, he's charmed.
Huge, huge!
Oh, and we get healing.
I am so back.
We are so back here, it's crazy.
Man, this one is rough.
Focus.
Wow.
Blow up, you son of a gun.
You son of a man!
I'm so dead.
So close to dying all the time.
I can't catch a brick.
Wow.
Oh, wow.
What was that?
Oh.
I have lots of money, though.
What are these little... are they going to hurt me?
Haha, no way.
Oh, you... it's a scam.
Okay.
Here.
Motherfucker!
Okay, oh.
No!
Wait, there's nothing in that.
This guy is scamming me.
I like this music.
Oh my god.
Huh!
Gambling!
Uh, I need healing, man.
Come on, healing!
What?
No!
Bro, if I had a bomb, I would blow the shit out of this guy right here.
For scamming me.
This was the worst arcade of all time.
More gambling in here.
Ah, I didn't even see that!
I had no idea that thing was there, I didn't even see it.
That is unbelievable, I died to an object with spikes on it.
That's horrible.
Okay, this was good practice, this was warm up, because now I'm going to my boy Azazel.
And my boy Azazel can't lose.
Because he's actually overpowered.
Look at this guy right here.
Oh, man.
We're going.
Wow.
He already freaking got some HP taken from us, what's that?
Yo, listen!
Beelzebub!
Plus one lock.
Fly familiar that wanders around the room and reveals the locations of tinted rocks, trap doors on the rocks, and secret room entrances.
That's insane.
Wait, is that a reference to Zelda?
You know, the little guy going, hey, listen!
I also have a fool teleport to the starting room on the current floor.
Oh, my God.
I can also change direction with this guy.
I had it configured to top, but now I changed it to right.
Oh, that's so much better.
There we go.
Where's that sound?
Oh, oh, wait, oh!
Oh, you're telling me there's something there.
Okay, I got it, I got it.
I don't have a bomb, though.
I see how it works.
Are you saying this rock is good?
That's a good rock?
I don't have any bombs, though.
I'll see you later.
Ja!
Wow, they came flying at me.
Rotten penny?
Wealth of flies.
Responsible blue fly when picking up coins?
Okay, sure.
Destroy these.
Oh, I'm gonna grab that.
Okay, I have a bomb now.
Wait, oh, you're saying there's something here.
Thank you!
Oh, my God.
Look at all this stuff.
The hanged man, may you find enlightenment?
Grant's flight for the room?
Whoa!
But I am already flying.
This would have been better on Victor.
Or whatever his name was.
What is his name?
Victor.
I don't even get that.
I don't know.
Let's go back.
Uh, Tabbo?
Are you trying to tell me something?
Okay.
Trying to tell me a tale, perhaps?
Whoa!
Uh, wait, hold on.
Flat file causes all spikes and obstacles, doors, and chests to retract.
I don't need that, because I'm flying.
Wait, I can just keep opening the chest?
How is that...
Wait, what's happening?
Why can I do this?
Oh, we're done?
Okay.
Oh, there's a secret here.
Dude, I love this guy.
Okay.
I'm so fast, too.
Dude, I just had an idea.
What if I had pushed these to a wall and then destroyed them?
That's some big brain right there.
I can totally utilize the pushing.
Uh, wait, what was this one again?
Yeah, I want this one instead.
No more from me here!
Too bad.
Uh, should I enter the boss room?
No, I have 15 coins!
We gotta go to the shop!
Is that a knife?
We're gonna get it.
Ventricle razor?
Can create two linked tunnel openings which allow Isaac to teleport between them?
What the fuck are you talking about?
Okay, we gotta try that.
Right now.
I'm an idiot!
Oh, dude.
Why do they have Q, which is to the top left of the keyboard, affect the item in the bottom right, and have the bottom right keybind affect the top left?
Am I crazy?
That's a horror.
I need to change it if I can.
Sick!
Alright.
Neat.
Let's kill him.
I need to remember to utilize the fact that I can go over rocks.
Uh, walnut.
That's a hard nut to crack.
It is, indeed.
Being hit by an explosion has a 33% chance to destroy the trinket and spawn one coin, one key, and one trinket.
Ha!
Um...
I don't want to get hit by an explosion.
I'm sorry.
That sounds horrible.
Absolutely not.
Should I go in here?
I have limited HP.
I think it's a bad idea.
We can't do it.
That is a horrible idea.
Up here.
Wow!
You're a big guy!
You're gonna jump?
Okay.
Chat, the little guy's gonna fuck me up.
I don't have enough range.
This is bad.
Okay, that's good, that's good.
I'm gonna die.
Kill the little guys.
This boss is crazy.
Oh, there's a little thing spawning there!
Get rid of that!
We gotta kill the boss right now.
It's the only thing we can do.
It's over!
Jump!
Drop, you asshole!
We got you!
Oh no, I can't heal!
Oh no.
It's over.
This is a horrible situation.
Oh, this healing, I can't take it.
Kill that shit.
This boss was nuts.
Consolation prize?
Again?
Okay.
Right.
Okay, are you telling me there's something over there?
That's right, we gotta listen to this fly.
They're gonna tell us that something is happening here.
One of these rooms had more secrets, right?
Yeah, here, this rock.
Whoa!
Hello!
What?
Hahaha!
Is that an enemy?
Timmy's head.
Tammy's head.
Fire is a ring of ten tears.
Okay.
And that's on space, not Q.
Space.
Fire is a ring of ten tears.
Um...
Okay.
Very cool.
Go back.
Yeah, we're leaving.
Man, I wish I could heal.
One hit and I'm down, you know?
Like, it's over.
Just threw a ball in my face and laughed at me.
Man, the childhood of Isaac has not been good, huh?
Man, I've been burned by the arcade so many times.
I'm gonna do it again.
This better be good.
Okay, so wait, this guy wants keys?
You want coins?
And you want hearts that I don't have?
Yeah, absolutely not.
You can have coins.
At least it's no shell game.
Come on.
I swear to God, this arcade!
Fuck!
Give me something I can use!
Oh!
Midnight snack.
Huge!
Massive!
Alright, moving on.
That's what I needed.
Oh, shit.
I gotta kill this guy.
Man, not having a lot of range here is brutal.
Okay, okay.
Oh, there's a secret here.
Thanks, Tatl.
The Emperor.
That's a good one.
That's more damage.
No, wait, that was the Empress, right?
I actually forgot.
Oh, this is teleports of boss room.
Never mind.
Okay.
Wait, what if I use this on you?
You like that?
You like?
Okay, you don't like that.
You hate it.
Up here.
Ouch!
Oh, I lost my black heart.
Oh, crap.
I'm in trouble.
This is not good.
At least I can heal, though, with this heart.
Right?
Oh, I'm an idiot.
I should have brought that down here.
Uh, open here.
What is this?
I can't buy it anyway.
I can't buy anything, actually.
I think I will donate.
Boom.
I donated.
That's hopefully going to do good things for me.
Okay, we got enemies.
Oh, yeah.
This is ideal for a sizzle.
How did you hit me?
You bastard.
There's a heart down here, though.
Uh, wait.
Wait, there's a secret room here.
Oh.
Right.
So, wait, does that mean I can access here?
No.
Table will tell me.
Thank you, Sharon.
Okay, that's good.
Oh, no.
Huge.
Got him.
That was a bit risky there.
Uh, this is a...
Okay, so what is this room?
There's two swords and a skull.
Let's see what it is.
Oh, it's like one of these challenge rooms, right?
So, I take this and then enemies come.
The belt, I get speed.
Still don't understand that one.
Ooh, yay, yay.
Man, the short range is brutal.
Wow.
It's a whole ass boss.
Oh.
What are you going to do?
Are you going to...
Yeah, are you going to do that?
I'm not going to risk it here.
What are you doing?
Are you going to shoot at me?
I got him.
Massive.
Shot speed down.
No.
I don't like that.
Boo.
Tatl, you better speak to me and tell me where there's HP.
Oh, wow.
Oh, I can totally abuse the rain here.
Oh, this is great.
Guys?
Oh, my God.
Why is this guy golden?
Boom.
Nailed it.
What happened?
Did I get some kind of item?
No.
What's that?
Harry's ramming speed.
0.25 speed.
When moving fast enough, running into enemies will deal contact damage to the enemy and prevent contact damage dealt to Isaac.
How fast is fast?
How fast do I need to move?
I can't play around with this.
Oh, wait, there's enemies here.
What was this active that I had?
Fire's a ring of ten tiers, right?
Okay.
I guess I'll save it for the boss.
Fuck it!
Oh, wow.
I thought I was going to die there.
That's why I used it.
Oh, I have mana again, so that's fine.
Uh-oh.
What is that?
This is like that video of the cops arriving at that fraternity or whatever.
It's the exact same thing.
What are they doing?
Hahaha!
Oh, yeah!
Not too shabby.
It's boss time.
With half a heart.
Wish me luck.
Monstro, we're going to use the active here.
Whoa!
Dude, there's no way I'm going to survive this.
Okay, ads are gone.
Almost.
She's...
Little guy.
You going to jump?
Not yet.
I got him!
Oh, man.
Oh, man, oh, man.
Mom's coin purse.
Oh, right, pills.
Bombs are key.
Really?
Balls of steel.
What is that?
Oh, I can't see it, I guess.
Um, okay.
Oh, speed up!
Excellent.
I don't... Does that even do anything other than me just peeing my pants?
I don't mind peeing my pants.
It's fine.
The emperor.
We're leaving.
Level three.
Oh, what is this music?
Whoa, look at this place!
Uh, I do have HP to go in there now, but I don't want to do it.
I'm going to lose HP.
And it's not good for me!
Wow!
How are you not dead?
No!
I lost all my HP!
What a room!
I'm going to gamble!
Dude!
Wait, bombs are key, right?
So what does that mean?
What does that mean?
What's that?
Play-Doh cookie.
Tasty rainbow.
Each tier Isaac fires gains a random color, granting it special bonus attributes.
The bonus attributes can be poison, fear, slow, freeze, charm, petrified, burning, exploding, homing, bait, 2x damage, reduce damage, no effect!
What the frick?
Interesting.
Is this going to completely fuck me, or what?
This sounds really weird.
Definitely some colorful shots there.
Gamble, gamble!
Oh, thanks.
Give me money.
Dude, I am moving so frickin' fast!
Does this mean if I move like this, am I actually just going to bump into enemies?
I can't risk it, though, with 1 HP.
I don't want to test this.
Gonna shoot, you gonna shoot, or what?
No, I got hit!
Holy crap!
It's over.
Fuck.
I can't fly... Oh, there's a secret here.
Thanks, Tatl.
Money.
Oh, we have a store here.
The money is good.
Shit.
Store is all the way at the top.
Dude, I'm so frickin' fast, what the hell?
Uh, here.
Oh, I can't go that way?
Oh, it's here.
I can't read a map.
That's fine.
No health, let me get it to 60.
Nothing happens.
What even is this thing?
Guess we don't know.
Okay, okay, okay, there's a room over here.
Oh, no.
Wow, golden horseshoe, feeling lucky?
Oh, 15% chance for the treasure room to contain 2 items to choose between.
This is worded in a way that makes me think that there's always a so-called treasure room.
Which one is the treasure room?
Oh, maybe it's actually the golden crown.
Maybe that's the treasure room.
Yeah, that would make sense, I guess.
Dude, I'm rich, what the hell?
Oh, no, give me this.
Um, let's go here and buy this thing.
Wooden voodoo head.
Something about cursing.
Spawns an additional curse room on each new floor when possible.
Improved layouts and rewards within curse rooms.
Also causes one coin to spawn in each curse room.
I wonder if the curse room is the room where I pick up an item and I lose an HP.
Maybe that's what the curse room is, because you get cursed with a lower HP.
Could also be a room that I never encountered and you actually get cursed with something.
Like a debuff, you know?
Uh, what was this down here?
Oh, man, I kind of want to get those pills, but I can't really do it.
Shit.
Wow.
Oh, man, man, man, oh, man.
Oh, wait, I can...
I'm so smart.
Okay, what's this?
Oh, no.
It's fine, I can just avoid you.
Uh-oh.
Are they gonna...
Okay, thankfully they didn't shoot any projectiles at me.
Pills!
I can see forever.
Cool.
Lock up.
I can see forever more.
48 hour energy.
Does that mean I have infinite energy?
That does not mean I have infinite energy.
Shots be...
No!
Nope.
Not taking that.
The Emperor, what was that one?
Teleport to the boss room.
Uh...
Shit, okay, let's just go.
Dude, I'm at a half heart!
This is insanity.
Okay, so this room is not open.
Yeah, and I'm at 36% demon mode, so maybe that is what's going on.
I don't know what that is.
Wait, where am I supposed to go?
I'm confused.
I guess I can teleport to the boss room?
Oh, wait, there's a room here.
Uh-oh!
Shit.
Dude, I am so on edge!
Kill these spiders.
Oh, that's my friend.
Don't you birth anything!
Hold on, my watch.
The moon!
May you find all you have lost?
Teleport to the secret room?
I'm gonna do it.
It's Q.
Oh.
Oh, okay, so the secret room is the one with the question mark.
Got it!
Okay, good to know.
Uh-oh.
Shit.
Ah!
Wow.
Oi, yoi, yoi.
Uh, you're somewhat poisoned?
What was that?
Now, I don't know what these heat buffs are.
Oh, no, they're shooting.
They're shooting at each other.
No, they're shooting little guys.
Okay.
Oh, man.
Oh, man, oh, man.
Oh.
Okay.
Let's go up here.
Uh-oh.
Oh, stay in the water, stay in the water.
I'ma wait, they can shoot, so...
okay.
Oh, you got frozen.
The hell?
Man, Azazel is just a glass cannon, huh?
A crazy character.
Oh!
My heart was in my throat for the past half hour.
Like, I was literally vibrating.
My legs were, like, doing the nervous tick thing.
Just, you know, up and down.
Throughout the entire thing.
It's crazy.
I'm gonna take a quick break.
I need it.
I'll be back in five minutes.
I'll see you guys.
Alright, let's go.
There it is.
I...
This is getting personal.
Oh, yeah.
Let's do Azazel again.
This time, I am not gonna risk anything.
I am gonna play so incredibly safe.
Because I think my problem is I wanna gamble too much.
You know, I see an opportunity where I can lose some HP for something, and I choose to go for it every time.
We are gonna change things up this time.
It'll be good.
Trust.
You know what would be really good on Azazel?
Getting some range.
Uh, you know?
Oh, nice.
Hey, getting money already.
That's pretty good.
A glass of milk?
Don't cry over it.
It's a familiar.
Follows Isaac and blocks projectiles.
After 10 hits, the glass breaks and Isaac gains plus one fire rate for the floor.
Ha!
Interesting.
I feel like it's never gonna hit 10 hits, though.
Like, no way.
This is a useless item.
I'm calling it right now.
Because I'm not gonna take any damage.
How is this gonna be absorbing anything?
I couldn't even say that with a straight face.
Ah, I'm kidding, of course.
Um, okay, so we got a weird room over here.
Ah, that's the room where I step on spikes and I get a coin.
Potentially something else as well, but I'm not gonna do it.
Not with this character.
Absolutely not.
Alright, so the gray one shoots.
Got him.
Eliminated.
Look at these little poops.
Oh, that's so satisfying.
Oh, what's that?
Booster pack.
Spawns five random cards on pickup.
That doesn't seem very good, does it?
Oh, we got a one-eyed dude.
He's now dead.
That's it!
This episode will now be called, The One-Eyed Man.
That's all I needed.
Any excuse?
Ah, there's a bomb here.
Oh, not this guy.
Kill it fast!
Before he causes any issues.
Sazel is actually fantastic, isn't he?
He's just so good.
What's this?
Bob's bladder.
Who's Bob?
One of three?
Placing a bomb also creates a small pool of high-damaging creep.
What is creep considered here?
I guess it's like Starcraft, where you have this sort of stuff on the floor.
You know?
Placing a bomb also creates...
Okay, I guess we're gonna try it.
The boss is here.
Ah, I'm not gonna go up there.
I'm gonna fight him.
The Duke of Flies.
Let me try this.
Oh, I don't have any bombs.
Rip.
Man, the Duke of Flies just gets cleared by the laser.
Whoa!
That is so good.
Wait, we got more milk.
Oh, no, it's breakfast.
Breakfast with milk!
This is the insane combo of all time.
We're getting a whole meal here.
Dude, that is so huge on this character, too.
I feel like...
Ah, I'm not gonna go up there.
Play it safe.
This is gonna be good.
So there's a timer on this one!
Mama's watching TV, and I'm upstairs being a little...
I keep wanting to say semen, but it's not quite the same, is it?
Oh, shit.
You know what I should be doing from now on?
Just hit and run.
That sort of stuff, you know?
That's good.
Mm, up here.
Hey, look at me flying!
Ain't that grand.
Oh, my God.
I love flying!
It's a picture of my mom, or what?
That is my mom with...
Is that a head she's holding?
Yikes.
Okay.
And a key.
Dude, I love flying.
It's actually changing everything for me.
What's that?
The devil.
X plus two damage for the room.
Oh, that's cool.
Hey, what did I have before?
The fool.
Teleport to the starting room.
Why do I ever want to do that?
Oh, I guess...
You know what?
It would be good if you enter one of those rooms where you take damage upon entering.
Then you get back out without taking damage.
Ah, I see the use case.
I do.
Now, the devil, I'm going to use that in the boss room.
Let me pick this up until we reach the boss room.
Just in case I need to use it.
I see how I'm going to utilize this now.
The fraternity's here.
Wonderful.
Oh, God, these guys are not that scary.
They're actually the best enemies in the game.
I like this.
Makes me happy.
Wow.
Hide behind the poop.
Oh, wait, these can fly, so it doesn't matter.
Is that dead end?
It's already going much better.
You run around.
Push.
No coins for me.
I have six coins.
I don't think I should open that, even though I have five keys.
I'm going to wait until I have more money.
I want to make it worth it.
Oh, I can stay in the center.
Look at this.
Wait for them to get close.
I'm playing it so safe.
Oh, my God, that's amazing.
It feels a little bit dirty.
Okay, I'm definitely going in here.
Item snatcher?
Pulls pickup items toward Isaac.
Automatically opens nearby chests, except locked and stone chests.
Well, that's not going to help me, because I'm Azazel.
So what, it's just going to fly off screen, or what?
Kill him.
I'm kidding, by the way.
I'm sure that is supposed to mean Azazel in the description there.
This guy's on fire.
Oh, wow.
Just like that.
I get a heart, a blue heart.
It pays to be a firefighter.
Okay, I guess it's time for the boss room.
No, let's go to the store first, just to see what they have on offer.
I do have four keys, right?
It should be okay.
I think it's worth.
I can buy a pill.
Now, you know what?
Let's actually try and save money.
Let's really try and save up money until we find a store that has something exciting.
I spent too much money.
You know, it's time to be frugal.
That's the word for that.
I'm going to pick this up, so we get plus two damage.
I'm going to use it in here, and that is Q on that one.
The gurglings.
They're going to be gurgling on me.
Oh!
That damaged me.
Wow, they died quick.
That plus two damage really did something there.
Matchbook, evil up?
Evil up?
Matchstick?
Tastes like burning.
Wait a minute.
Plus one black heart.
Oh, that's cool.
Spawns three bombs.
Spawns matchstick, trinket.
Which is the one I just picked up.
10% increased chance of finding bombs.
As room clear rewards.
33% chance to add an additional bomb to chests.
Tinted rocks and destroyed machines.
How do I actually scroll down here?
I...
I'm pressing all the buttons.
There's like a scroll thing.
Maybe a scroll wheel?
No.
I don't know how to... There's like a little scroll icon.
Okay, I don't know.
No clue.
So what about these weird poops?
Did that just damage me?
Oh, they come back.
Oh, those little bastards.
I want to see what the last thing is down there.
Oh well.
I can go in here?
Oh, it's this stuff again.
I don't know if I should do it.
Kill these things.
I wonder if this is going to take a black heart or my red heart.
I mean, the icon is obviously red.
So...
No.
I said we're going to play safe.
We're playing safe.
Stick to it.
Okay, now.
Get those tomatoes out of the way before they grow too fat.
Nice.
That was clean.
Surgical.
Wait, I can just... I can circumvent it.
That feels amazing.
Moms pearls.
Range plus lock up.
Yo, that's cool.
Range.
Whoo!
Huge.
So this is also part of a set or something.
One out of three.
I kind of want to try and complete one of these sets.
That should be a goal of mine now.
Golden poop is good.
You need to die.
There we go.
Wait for them to overlap like that.
That's smart gaming.
So this was just a bunch of gold, right?
Yeah.
Nice.
I do have a lot of money, but...
I want to wait until I have 15, because some items cost 15.
It's like 5, 7 and 15, it seems.
What is that?
Oh, this thing.
Huh?
What did I do?
Oh, I get it.
It's like a...
It's a die.
There's three circles on it.
What does that mean?
I didn't pick anything.
I think I may have done something to the...
Oh, look at the way it's being sucked towards me.
That's neat.
Rotten penny?
Wait, was this here before?
Have things changed?
Did something change in here?
Oh, God.
Oh, wow!
Get those little guys out of the way.
The fact that I can just fly over here is nuts.
I like that my devil horns are now the magnets, you know?
I'm not going to go in yet.
Not yet.
I have things to do.
Okay, these guys are crazy.
Oh, man, how am I going to do this?
Jesus!
I had to do it.
I had to do it like that.
It was all the way.
These guys were nuts.
Oh, that's big!
Use diaper?
You stink?
What the fuck?
33% chance to gain the scatole effect for the room.
Or scatole?
Scatole?
I don't know what's better here.
Is it good to have scat?
That doesn't sound good to me.
What's that?
Latch key.
Lock.
Oh, that's a lot of keys.
Come here, guys.
Oh, God.
Beautiful.
Boom!
There's more.
You're dead.
Are you going to shoot?
You are going to shoot.
Oh, it's homing!
Yeah, they're homing.
Purple is homing.
That's great information.
Okay.
The sun.
They delight, heal, and enlighten you.
Feels a hundred damage to all enemies.
Wow!
That is a crazy card!
Whoa!
What the shit?
I need to remember that one.
I have to remember it's Q.
It's Q if I want to use it.
Fucking hell!
Damn, son!
Uh, man, should I try and go in there?
I have so many HPs.
I could do it.
Let's do it.
Oh, wait, what?
Push!
I didn't lose any HP.
Did I block it with my milk?
Wait, where's my milk?
No, I have it.
I have the milk.
I don't know what just happened.
Either that or...
Wait, let me go through again.
No, okay, yeah, I think I blocked it with my milk.
Man!
What a waste.
What's that?
Virgo, you feel refreshed and protected.
Chance when taking damage to activate a shield for ten seconds.
Chance increases with luck.
I have a lot of luck!
Converts negative pill effects into positive ones.
Yo!
That's kind of dope.
That means every pill is good.
Very good, very good.
We have a shop room and boss.
I'm going to the shop room because I am rich!
Holy shit, 24 gold coins in my account.
I'm buying it.
Sharp key, open your enemies?
Oh, that sounds horrible.
Plus five keys.
Consumes one key to launch a sharpened key projectile in the direction of your choice.
Oh, it's an active.
The key damages and pierces enemies and can also open the first lock.
Or destroy the first obstacle it collides with.
That doesn't sound that good.
That doesn't sound good at all.
I don't want to use my keys on damaging the enemy.
That's horrible.
Should I donate money?
No.
No, no, no.
We're betting everything on this run right now.
This run is nuts.
I like the little bow we have.
Where's that from?
Where's that coming from?
I don't know.
Look at the little bow we have in our hair.
Beautiful.
It's like a little sweet demon.
Sweetest demon there was.
All right, it's boss time.
Hestilence.
Yo, a new one.
I'm going to use this.
My trump card.
Oh, I guess the green stuff is bad.
Don't stand in the green stuff.
Like an ex-ramas boss.
Oh, God.
Just kill him.
Honestly, yeah, get him out of here.
The Book of Revelations.
Oh, I did that really well.
I almost didn't lose any HP.
Cube of meat.
Gotta meat them all.
Levels up each time it is collected.
One, orbital familiar that blocks shots and deals contact damage.
Two, orbital familiar that blocks shots, deals contact damage, and fires shots.
And three, familiar that chases and damages enemies.
And four, bigger familiar that chases and damages enemies.
What are the chances of finding four of these in one run?
Like, there's like a million items in this game.
That seems almost incredibly impossible.
Yeah.
Oh, there's a secret.
There's a secret here.
What the...
Hell yeah.
Okay, all pills are good.
Ooh, massive.
Let's go get health.
Man, that's good.
That's real good.
Okay, I guess we can move on now.
All right, stage four.
We got these weird breast squirts.
What is that drawing supposed to be?
I can't decipher it.
Okay, this door is locked now.
I don't know why.
I really don't understand the mechanics there.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Cartridge!
Whoa.
Five percent chance to trigger the game kit effect when taking damage.
Oh, is that the one where I go bleep, bleep, bleep, bleep, like Pac-Man?
Doesn't sound that good, honestly.
Uh, I think I'll rather have the used diaper.
By the way, the used diaper, it had an effect about spawning a fly, but...
Man, I wish I could scroll down.
Remind me, guys, when I ask you after the stream, tell me how to scroll down, okay?
I need this information in my life.
Okay, watch this, this is so smart.
Yeah!
Huge!
And the magnet!
The magnet!
So good.
Okay, this way.
Aha!
What's that?
Tape worm.
What does that say, floor?
Plus three range.
Wait, that's a lot, isn't it?
No, gimme that.
Oh, that's huge!
I love that.
Oh, wow!
Look at all these guys!
Insanity.
This room looks to be really difficult if you're playing as Isaac.
Okay, the arcade.
Man, should I be going in there?
I'm gonna... not this guy again.
Okay, I give you one more chance.
Okay, asshole.
It's here.
You...
Okay, hold on.
What if I stand on top of it as soon as he reveals it?
Maybe I can snatch it from him.
No, I couldn't.
Okay, it's one of the sides.
It's this one.
Bro!
Again.
Okay, so I'm really looking.
It's here.
How is... like, just RNG?
Statistically, this can't be real.
He's scamming.
I don't believe it.
There's a 33% chance.
No, no, no, no, I'm being scammed.
This asshole is just out of control.
You know what?
Fuck you.
Oh!
Wait, I get all the money back?
Wait a minute.
So wait, I can feed the money.
Chance of something good.
And if I run out of money, I blow him up and get my money back?
No way!
No frickin' way!
Okay, guys, come here.
Whoa.
Are you gonna shoot?
You are gonna shoot.
Kill him!
Wow.
Get him!
Man, this extra range is so frickin' nice.
Feels good.
Feels real good.
Dude, I kinda wanna listen to Dr. Feel Good.
You know why?
Because he makes me feel good.
It's a great song.
It always makes me happy.
Not that I need to be more happy right now.
I'm very happy with the situation.
This is everything I ever wanted.
I'm actually owning.
Oh, I'm owning!
Kill him.
This guy needs to die now.
Boom!
What's that?
Tick!
Well, that's not coming off.
Is it not?
When entering the boss room, restores one Red Heart and removes 15% health from the boss.
Whoa!
But there's more effects that I can't read.
Hold on.
Maybe page down?
No.
Okay.
Let me see the difference here.
So I stand here.
Oh, shit, it ain't coming off.
They weren't kidding!
No!
I was like, yeah, sure.
I'm just going to pick up the other thing.
That's how I'm going to get it off.
Nope.
Wow, they got me good with that one.
I got to be honest.
They got me.
I'm here.
Kill it.
These evil tomatoes need to die immediately.
That's the boss room?
Not entering yet.
I'm going down here instead.
Without range, this is actually kind of hard.
Wait, does my projectile destroy theirs?
No, not really.
Making progress.
I feel like I'm getting hit, but then I'm not getting hit.
Maybe it is the milk that's doing a lot of work.
Libra.
Minus speed, more tiers.
Less damage, less range.
Six bombs, six keys, six coins?
Stat upgrades are balanced among all stats.
I don't think that's good.
I like my current setup.
Like, this is a bad trade.
I already have keys, bombs, and coins.
When it says upgrades are balanced, it means that the lowest ones get raised up, right?
And the highest ones get...
No, no, no, I don't like that.
Nope.
Absolutely not.
I actually made a decision there, guys.
Can you believe it?
An educated decision here.
Oh god, this guy blows up.
I guess he's a bomb spider then.
Umbilical cord.
Entering a room with half red heart or less.
Gaining a little Steven familiar that fires homing tears.
30% chance when taking damage to spawn a Gemini familiar for the current room.
Chant increases with luck.
Oh wait,
I can't even pick it up.
Oh, it's one of those items in the bottom left.
I see, okay.
That's why I can't pick it up.
Got it.
What did this one, the tick, even do to me?
Restores one red heart and removes...
Okay, I mean, that's pretty good, I guess.
Wow!
Holy fucking shit, this room was insane.
Oh no.
You gotta be kidding me.
I'm throwing.
It's going horribly.
I think this is considered creep.
Can't go in there.
What the frick is that?
I don't know what it is, but I don't like it.
Man, oh man.
The coin was floating on the water there.
That's weird.
Nice.
Uh oh.
Yeah.
You spawned spiders.
Thank you.
I got 14.
Oh, what the...
I got bamboozled!
This was not a real shop room.
No!
Oh my god.
It's not going well, guys.
Steam sale.
Okay, well...
That's cool and all, but...
We're gonna need shops for that.
Okay, there's a weird room up here.
Maybe it's open now.
No, it's not open.
Why is that?
Yeah, whatever.
Let's go to the boss.
It's boss time.
What about the arcade?
Oh, I could gamble at 20!
Ooh, should I gamble?
Oh!
No, I didn't.
No, I don't want that.
That's a good pill?
Telepills.
Gimme more.
Hey!
Oh my god, I'm winning!
Oh, come on.
Oh my god.
Best gambling session ever.
Lock up!
That means I'm gonna get even more winnings!
More!
I'm so lucky!
I'm lucky, right?
Huh?
No, no, okay, that's bad.
I don't like that.
I don't like that at all.
Ro, come on.
Come on.
Okay, well...
Okay, fuck you.
I'm gonna save my remaining money.
Let's go up here.
This way.
It's time for the boss.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Uh...
Let me just review everything.
What is this meat thingy?
The one that levels up, it's weird.
Uh, let me have this one.
Oh wait, so...
Oh, right, so I can actually press space now.
And do this.
If damage isn't pierced...
We can try that, I guess.
It's peep.
Oh, that did a lot of damage?
Eh, not that much, actually.
Oh my god!
Uh, do your thing, man.
Just kill him fast.
Honestly...
Get him out of here.
Wow.
Okay, good.
Uh, what's this?
Synth oil.
Damage?
Oh, that's good.
That's just straight up good.
That's good right there.
Okay.
Flower for the girl!
Oh, my pee pee is showing.
Why are people so mean?
I like the whispering here in this area.
This is cool.
Nice.
Wait, you can't die!
Wow!
Huh?
Okay, there we go.
See ya!
What happened?
Oh, we got flies?
Okay.
Wait, I can't leave.
Once I enter, I'm here forever.
These are gonna explode.
Dude, I have crazy range now, look at this!
Oi!
Sniper!
Amazing.
Okay.
Wonderful.
Dude, should I just go straight for the boss like a madman?
No, no, no, let's not do it.
It's a bad idea.
Bad idea.
I don't like it.
Ooh, I like that though.
In fact, I enjoyed that quite a bit.
This room is open!
Oh wait, what?
Holy shit!
That's huge!
Uh oh.
These guys are dangerous.
What happened?
Okay, okay.
Wow!
There you are.
Gotta be fast with these guys.
Oh, oh, oh!
Okay then.
Uh oh, what's this?
It's gonna attack me and I'm gonna have a bad time.
Hey, I knew it, I knew it!
Oh, rotating children.
I feel so broken when I can do this.
Oh, you can't hit me at all, can you?
Okay, oh, oh, oh!
Oh, nice, nice.
Okay, they go up and down.
So what is that big key there?
You heard that?
Something in the distance just unlocked.
Ooh, what is it?
Something unlocked in the distance.
In the depths.
Uh oh.
Wow!
Oh my god.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, man.
Man, the stars!
Teleport to the treasure room.
If there is a planetarium, teleport to it instead.
Oh my god, let's try it.
Is this the treasure room?
It is.
What is that?
Rosary.
Ha, nice!
Now I can ascend to the citadel.
Uh, let's see here.
Seraphim, one of three.
More tears, three soul hearts!
Whoa!
Nice!
And, what else?
Adds copies of the bible to all item pools?
Okay.
We're getting religious.
We shall learn from the teachings.
Wait, there's apparently a boss.
Oh wait, nevermind, I misread where I was.
Ah, the red one is evil!
Oh, dear lord.
Ah, I shouldn't have been that close, that was a mistake.
Uh, I missed the room back here.
Oh god, the explosion!
You cannot underestimate that.
Very good, very good.
Man, I like this soundtrack for this stage here.
This is really nice.
I don't know what that was just now, but he died.
He dead.
More bombs, more batteries, I don't need that.
I do need this.
Holy crack!
I have a lot of money!
Yipsy daisy!
Is blue fire evil?
I think it's evil.
Oh man, I wish I could take out the blue fire.
Oh my god, it's a super sasyl?
Is that what it said?
Well, you ate nothing to me.
How come these shop rooms are all messed up?
I want to buy things, I have money.
Oh, whoa!
Nice trick you got there.
That's beautiful.
What's up with all the money?
We gotta hit the arcade.
Oh, this red thing's gonna come back.
Yep, yep, yep, yep, yep.
Yeah, that was bad.
I touched the red poop, and I paid the iron price.
What the hell is this room?
I don't trust like that, watch.
Yeah, boy.
Okay, so what's happening here?
Obviously, there's something going on here.
I'm gonna blow them up.
Nice!
Okay.
Uh,
milk just splattered everywhere.
Interesting.
Uh, I guess it's boss time.
Let's go to the boss.
I'm gonna smack his ass.
Ooh, yeah.
Smack time!
It's Loki!
Loki kinda cool.
Uh, you were like, I'm gonna smack you.
You're over there now?
Okay, you're over there now?
That's cool.
You are the worst boss I've ever seen in my life.
Like, what are you even doing right now?
You're terrible!
Remove his boss rights!
Crackjacks!
What?
Sounds awesome.
Familiar?
No, that's not crackjacks, that's milk.
But we have milk with the crackjacks!
That should be a fantastic combo, no?
More health?
Random trinket.
Ah, but I can't take it because...
Whoa!
Oh!
Oh, that one is so good!
I gotta take that one, but...
Should I try a new one?
Ooh, I feel like I gotta take this one.
It's too good!
I gotta take it.
Oh!
The holy shield, baby!
It's an angel!
I kinda wanna blow the angel!
Okay.
Nevermind.
Let's go in here.
Okay, we're wearing a dress and people make fun of us.
But you know what?
We're gonna use those experiences as a child and channel it into rage and anger.
Meaning damage.
Oh, whoa!
Kill this guy!
Oh, man.
Sazio is unstoppable.
He is the best.
And...
go!
Ah-ha!
I can just fly, bitch!
It's a ring.
Mom's ring!
Damage up!
Two out of three now!
Spawns one random rune or soul stone on pickup.
Rune or soul stone, huh?
Huh?
Did I pick something up?
Did I pick a rune or a soul stone up?
I'm not sure.
There's no rune.
I was lied to.
Why are you always lying?
Oh my god.
Stop fucking lying.
I have infinite keys.
Okay, so yeah, it's six-sided dice now.
Is that good?
Maybe that's good.
Oh, more bombs?
Dude, I have so many bombs.
What the hell?
Pills.
Pretty fly.
Or a white guy.
Okay.
Oh!
I lost a bunch of stats!
But I gained some other stats.
What the frick?
I'm yellow.
Wait a minute.
How the fucking phone?
All my shit is gone!
Three dollar bill.
Does that even exist?
Grants random tier effects that cycle every six seconds.
Huh.
Contagion.
The first enemy killed in each room explodes, and poisons nearby enemies.
Poisoned enemies also explode on death, spreading the poison to more enemies.
Holy shit!
Okay.
That's insanity.
Spawns red heart.
Key.
Okay, well.
Rosary.
I still have that.
Pack of cards.
Mom's lipstick.
Spawns a red heart on pickup.
Mom's pearls.
Odd mushroom.
Okay.
Number one.
Oh, that's a lot of minus range.
Tears turn yellow, and fire from lower?
I don't know what that means.
Pageant boy.
Spawn seven random coins and one random penny trinket on pickup.
I guess I lose all of these on pickup effects, then.
Thunder thighs.
What a name.
Why is it a bucket of piss?
Huh?
Heals one red heart.
Isaac can break most obstacles by walking over them.
Except I'm not walking.
Knockout drops?
Chance to fire fist shots.
Which have much stronger knockback and confuse enemies for several seconds on impact.
Okay, okay.
This is, I guess I just sort of...
Look at Isaac!
I mean, it's Azazel.
He's all messed up.
His face looks like, I don't know.
Like he has some kind of skin disease.
Wait, wait, am I gaining random stats when I enter a room?
What is happening?
Wait, wait, wait.
What is doing that?
Huh?
Wait a second.
Oh, Grant's random tear effects that...
Oh, it's every six seconds?
That's what I said.
Uh, whoa!
Huh?
What is happening in this game?
I'm so confused!
Kill them all!
Poop!
I'm breaking rocks!
Oh, so I am walking on them, I guess.
Oh, buh buh buh buh buh buh buh!
Jesus Christ!
Holy crap, Benoli!
Kill them all!
A clipper!
Or a stapler, I mean.
Damage up, that's cool.
But does it matter, really?
I mean, everything is just fucking randomized here.
Kill them, nice.
Okay, okay.
Very good.
I'm super slow now, though, all of a sudden.
Because I don't have all the speed I had before.
Whoa, did you see that?
That was a spread on that one, that was cool.
These enemies are insane, by the way.
They're so difficult.
Thanks.
Open this.
Holy crap, a Rollie!
We're donating all of this!
You unlocked Cain!
New character?
Amazing.
Here we go!
I'm putting all my money in here.
Calm down, man!
Wait, it broke?
Ew.
Oh yeah, right, enemies explode, I have to remember this.
This is quite a big thing.
Wow.
Okay.
Huge!
Okay, then.
What is that?
Lazy worm.
I can't pick it up because I still have...
The goddamn tick is just impossible to get off, huh?
No matter what you do.
Okay.
You want hearts?
Fuck off!
I'm not getting any hearts.
Actually, wait.
What am I blowing you up after?
Should we do a test?
No, no, it will take my blue hearts, I think.
It's a bad idea, bad idea.
Back.
Go back.
Man, this run is insanity.
Absolute insanity.
Man, I'm actually super slow compared to what I was before.
I was flying down the street.
Just before all this disastrous happens.
What the...
That's a funny boss.
There was no way to escape that guy.
Buttons.
Ow!
Am I pooping every time I take damage?
Turn that crap off!
Man.
Wait, I'm flying.
Shouldn't I just not take damage from these?
Hey!
Well, okay.
I could've sworn I'd try that once, though.
Um, go in here.
Oh, not this again?
Wait, haven't I been in this room before?
What the...
Is that Mom?
Mom!
You're ugly!
You're disgusting!
Oh, yeah, I'm eating rocks.
That's true.
Just remember that.
Okay.
More bombs?
I have so many bombs.
What the heck?
Oh, yeah.
Why am I so rich?
Like, I have infinite money.
I need a proper store right now.
Uh...
Leech.
Bloodsucker.
Familia that chases and damages enemies.
Heels Isaac for half red heart.
When it's damaged, kills an enemy.
That sounds really good!
Holy...
Very nice.
Oh, I even break these?
Oh, no, I accidentally put a key inside the keystone.
Mistake.
Dude, should we just, like, start bombing walls with all these bombs?
Random... Let me go in here, actually.
Fuck it.
Wait, I didn't take any damage!
Why didn't I take half a heart?
Oh, my goodness!
What the frick?!
Oh, yeah, I should be safe here.
I was not expecting that to follow me, but okay, okay, okay, okay, I see your stance.
We're gonna blow shit up.
Because I'm rich in bombs.
What did I just take damage from?
Wait, what?
So, okay, so you take damage when you exit, but not when you enter.
When you're flying.
Why?
Blow it up.
I wonder if I can force my way in here.
One.
Nope, okay.
I'm not gonna try anymore.
There's a shop room.
47 gold is what I have, baby.
Oh, no, it was this bullshit.
Okay.
That's too bad.
Oh, no, wait, that's not the shop room.
Shop room is over here.
Never mind, guys, I'm delirious.
School bag has appeared.
Alright.
I'm buying this.
Battery pack?
Instant?
Oh, okay.
I don't really need that.
This is a shitty-ass shop.
Can I donate more?
Okay.
Very disappointing shop.
Now, okay, so this guy has a picture of a red heart.
I wonder if that will surpass or not touch my blue heart.
Let's try.
Okay, okay, good to know.
Come on, give me something.
You bastard.
So if I blow you up now...
I don't get my hearts back.
Okay, that's a scam.
I'm gonna go get some more hearts then.
I'm playing it super safe here.
Yoink.
Thank you.
Uh, did I have more?
There is another heart I can grab.
I will grab it.
There is amazing that I can fly over these spikes.
Shit.
Didn't mean to do that.
There you go.
Now we go back.
Time for the boss.
Do not donate another key.
Uh, okay.
Did I try blowing that up?
I think I did.
I really want to go in there.
But I can't.
Okay, I need to figure this out.
Okay, shit.
So that's what happens.
Now I know.
It just blows up.
I thought that bomb was for me.
Oh, it's mom!
Here we go!
Wait, wait, wait, I also have an active.
What is that?
Oh.
Random card.
The world?
Oh, man.
Just deal damage.
Wherever I can.
Ouch.
I'm using a lot of HP here.
Whoa!
I did it!
Rotten meat.
Yeah!
That's good.
Ooh, another one of these.
That's C Scrolls.
This is the one that grants me a random thingy.
Triggers another active item effect chosen at random.
Okay, I kind of like that.
Actually, I do like this one too, I guess.
You know what?
Let me try this.
I can't see the map.
Give me that.
Aha!
Secret room spotted!
Wait, I can't leave?
I...
Also, what is this?
I can jump down a hole there.
I don't want to do that.
Not yet.
I want to get back.
Oh!
No, okay.
Okay, crap.
All right.
Guess we're going in here.
Oh, we're going further!
We're dreaming of Ska...
Wow.
Even the sky is bullying us.
Whoa, are we in hell?
What is this?
Utero?
What?
No!
Not the uterus!
We're inside mom's uterus?
I don't like that.
Oh, God.
What the hell are you guys?
You have a lot of HP.
Jesus.
Wow.
Somehow they don't take damage.
Okay, so they're actually like those static ones, but they're flying now.
There we go.
See ya.
Bucket of lard?
Okay, HP up.
Oh man, again.
More HP, huh?
This is great!
Fantastic!
Oh man, this level is crazy looking.
Can I still eat rocks?
You can.
Oh, this music is scary.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Oh, yoy, yoy.
Oh, I thought I could, you know, quickly pass by there without them hitting me.
Oh, no.
This was a disaster.
What the?
Absolutely not.
Okay, okay.
Ew!
Little microcosms with little pieces of shit inside.
Get them out of here.
What the frick was that?
Whoa!
There we go.
Okay, up.
Dude, this is insanity.
He wants coins.
I have plenty.
And I just blow them up, and we get it all back.
Beautiful.
Hey.
I'm gonna save some money for a store, though.
Can I actually just keep doing this?
Yo.
Come on.
More health.
I need healing.
Oh.
The Empress.
That's a good one.
Plus 1.5 damage and something else that I can't see.
Okay, let me blow this guy up.
No!
I didn't get my money back.
Oh, okay.
That was a waste, I guess, but couldn't have known.
Jeez, did you see that attack, though?
What is happening?
Oh, okay.
You can't walk through those.
Got it.
I get it.
Holy cannoli, that's a lot of enemies.
Cool.
The boss is here.
How about no?
Not yet.
Wait, don't walk into...
These are good, right?
No, no.
Don't walk into any rocks.
Rocks are bad here, it seems.
These are uterus rocks.
You don't wanna, you know, scrape those and see what comes out.
There's a little bit of healing in here.
Apparently.
Wait, why's my charge so slow?
That's absolutely disgusting.
Oh, no!
I feel so slow in general, like...
This is gonna be a problem.
I can't dodge things properly.
Okay.
Mr. Me has appeared.
Broken remote.
Triggers to teleport affect each time an active item is used.
Oh, but I can't pick it up.
Did I just take damage?
I'm gonna go in here.
Yeah, I take no damage from entering.
He dead.
Oh.
Yeah.
Wow, wait, I take a full heart on the way back of them.
That was a full heart of damage just now.
This is the weirdest thing ever.
Oh!
Damn.
Oh, they're not dead yet.
There we go.
Wait, was there a pill?
There was a pill back there.
But I apparently missed.
I'm dying here.
This place is crazy.
Oh, there's a pill there.
Oh, no, this is bad.
I don't like retrovision.
Also, I should be using...
this active.
Pinking shears.
I don't even know what that means.
I'm dead.
I can't see anything.
No, it's over.
Oh, what a run though.
That was a crazy funny run.
Holy crap.
Guys, I gotta take a real mean piss.
I'm sorry, I'll be right back.
Okay.
I was actually thinking.
Oh, I didn't mean to...
I mean, we can do one more as Hazel, I guess.
But I was gonna say, why would I ever pick Isaac when I can pick Lazarus, who is exactly the same as Isaac?
Except he also can come back from the dead.
Maybe I missed something there.
Okay, this way.
Oh, no, not the spiders.
They're the worst.
Okay, that's totally fine.
I haven't seen this spider before.
Is he gonna blow up?
Oh, yeah, kind of.
Wait, why everything looks like this now again?
The fool, this one's gonna teleport me to the entrance?
Yeah.
I'm starting to get the hang of this.
Dude, that run was amazing just now.
I'm still on a high from that.
Oh, these little bastard spiders.
Oh, no, my range is so low.
Oh, kill it.
Oh, so they only spawn spiders when they're sort of fully grown, those sacks.
It's good to know.
Oh, okay, I was there already?
Uh-oh.
Hit the buttons.
Oh, what?
Sissy Longlegs, she loves you.
Okay.
Wandering Familia that spawns friendly blue attack spiders, applies charm to enemies on contact.
That sounds pretty good.
Why is this one...
Oh, these were the ones that had spikes in them, right?
Okay.
Moving on.
Oh, we got a crazy room here.
Technology 2, extra laser?
Whoa!
That's fucking cool!
Rainbow!
Wait, what did that do?
Minus tears replaces tears from the left eye with a continuous unlimited ranged laser.
Whoa, that seems really good.
Wow, that seems extremely good.
We got to really focus here.
Oh, this is nuts!
It's not a lot of damage, but it's still good, you know?
And then when things get close, I use my special attack.
Oh, that's a friend, okay.
Money me?
Uh, money room?
No, not yet.
This is insane.
I love this upgrade!
I'm going!
Fuck it!
Headless Horseman!
Wow, that's a new one.
Uh-oh.
Maybe not a good idea to start a new boss when we don't know what's happening!
He's charmed!
Yep, okay.
Get charmed, nerd!
Hey, there we go!
What's that?
A pony!
Flight plus dash attack.
Dash across the screen?
Isaac is invulnerable and deals contact damage while dashing.
Grant's flight while held increases speed to 1.5 while held.
If speed stat is below that.
Nice!
That's huge!
How does that work?
Let me see.
Uh, it would be space.
Holy shit!
Okay!
We go straight through the rooms as well!
Wait, really?
We can dash through walls?
Um...
I don't know if I should buy that.
Um, I don't know.
I don't know what that... what is this one?
Haven't had it before.
Kinda wanna buy it just to add it to the bank, you know?
Of knowledge.
Uh, there is a room up here I could enter...
No, but definitely not with the black hearts.
It's a bad idea.
I think I'll actually buy this.
Thanks.
See you later.
And I will leave.
I need to convert my black hearts to normal hearts.
That's the goal.
Seller two.
I like that the music changes as well.
Between runs.
It's really dope.
Nice.
That was a lot of money just now.
I was... I'm actually back at the money level I was at before.
Match, uh, book.
Nice.
One more black heart.
Three bombs.
Match the trinkets.
Sweet.
Hope we don't wanna play with matches in this room.
Can they actually cause a chain reaction?
Nice.
I'm an idiot.
Why did I do that?
Oh god!
Wait, I thought the blue one was an enemy.
The Empress.
I want this instead.
What's that?
Mongo, baby.
Mongo, baby!
Conjoined.
Familiar that fires tears at Isaac's base tier rate.
Copies the tier effects of other familiars.
Okay, cool.
Uh, yeah, wait.
I can, uh...
I can go over this.
What?!
Why, why?
Hello, inconsistency?
The fuck, man?
Bullshit.
Gimme that.
Okay, whatever.
I will kill everyone.
Dude, this laser is nuts.
Just use the small laser.
I don't care about the big one.
Uh, I don't wanna deal with that over there.
Stop crying.
There we go.
Man, my charge attack is so much better, though.
I'm just set at range here.
Played safe.
Oh, I have exactly 15.
Steam sale?
Could be good.
For later?
Yeah.
Why not?
I'm investing in the future.
I expect to get rich.
We got shit in here.
Oh, man, I love this laser that I have here.
It's so good.
Dude, I'm also pushing them back with this laser effect.
Very nice.
Good.
Going straight in.
The haunt!
Oh, we gotta kill the small ones first.
This is how that works.
Oh, wow.
Here we go.
He's mad now.
Oh, right.
He does that shit.
Stay at range.
Played safe.
Oh, we died.
Plot, plot, plus one damage and plus range for Isaac's left eye.
That's good, though, because this is my left eye.
I am very low on HP, though.
This is not...
I don't wanna enter there because this is one of those rooms.
But you have to give a heart to...
But here's the thing.
Let's see if the game is consistent.
Oh, fuck me.
Wait, what?
Wait, I can choose one of these, but I lose three blue, but I don't have any blue.
So I should be fine.
Right?
Like...
Oh, man.
I have such a good setup going.
Should I risk it all for the biscuit?
Uhhhhh...
I'm not gonna do it.
Fuck it.
I'm too frickin' scared.
Yeah, fuck that.
Nope.
We're going with one heart, and hope that we get more red hearts.
The game wasn't consistent with the spikes on the ground.
There's no reason it should be consistent with other things.
We unlocked a new character, too!
Nice.
Oh, my God.
Okay, there we go.
Uh, we have a weird room here that's open.
Owie, this is gonna spawn enemies.
We gotta be ready.
Shit.
That's unfair!
I was out of range!
What the fuck is that?
Man.
Are you kidding me?
I was all the way in the corner!
How did that hit me?
Okay, wait, this one has three life.
Two speed.
Let me see the difference, then.
Two speed and two attack.
Yeah, it's the exact same, except this guy is just better.
Why would you ever pick Isaac, then?
Also, what is greed?
Ah, it's probably, like, even harder, isn't it?
Like, next level difficulty.
Man.
Normal was super easy.
Hard is super hard.
Like, that is a crazy step up.
Uh, I wanna try... what is this?
So, two hearts, three boots, one attack.
Dead bird.
Whore of Babylon?
Eve!
We also have Cain.
Luckfoot.
I shall be the ho- Man, I have a Windstreak of- Wait a minute, that's not true!
Windstreak minus eleven?
I killed mom!
But I guess that was more after mom, so maybe it doesn't count.
Yeah, that's probably it, actually.
Okay.
I'm gonna try Eve, I'm the whore of Babylon!
Oh, we're in the emo phase.
I like it.
Don't you cry at me.
Crying is for normies, I'm an emo.
I'm cool.
I don't cry.
Oh, they spawn a lot of flies.
Is this kind of a crazy room, though?
Like, the first room we find is exceptionally crazy.
So, two hearts only, that's not a lot to work with here.
Uh, right, okay.
What's a Brava?
Oh, wait, I have a bird with me!
I see, so that's what that is.
Uh-huh.
Uh-oh.
This is gonna be trouble.
Fuck me!
Whoa!
Yo, this is hard as hell.
Kill him!
Oh, man!
The whore of Babylon is not very strong.
This is exceptionally low damage.
This bird better be worth it.
Where's the bird?
It's not even here.
I can't even hit these guys.
Nice!
Good stuff, that was a tough room.
Wow.
Oh, I miss flying.
Aw, man.
How is a Seizel not just, like, next-level OP compared to all the other characters?
Huh?
Whoa!
I got attacked, and then something happened.
Wait, did we just have sex with him?
Are we the whore of Babylon?
We just did something.
He came at us, and we were like, no, no, no, good sir.
I shall have your, you know, member.
And then this happened.
Okay.
That's a weird mechanic, though, so what happens now?
Wait, damage is 5.86.
I don't know what it was before.
It was definitely not that high, I don't think.
Maybe when we're at 1 HP, we just turn into this, you know, demon.
And we just do a lot of damage suddenly.
Maybe the strategy is to stay on low HP here.
Which is kind of scary.
Not yet, not yet, not yet.
That's crazy.
This way.
There's a whole room down here I didn't explore yet.
Oh, these guys are so dangerous.
I'm one-shotting them.
Wow!
That's pretty dang good.
Uh, wait, isn't this this German knurls?
You know the German website knurls?
This looks like a knurls.
Swoop the, oh, it's the swoop the swoop, of course.
Obviously.
Isaac fires a laser from his mouth.
There's no laser.
Oh, it's an active, I see.
I don't, so there's one thing I don't understand.
Some of these actives have, like, five battery stages to it.
This one has two.
But every time I use these, it consumes the whole battery.
So it's super confusing.
I thought it would use, like, one stage of the battery.
Like, this one has two charges, it seems.
Then it turns out it doesn't.
I guess we'll find out.
Well, swoop the, swoop sounds incredibly powerful.
We're gonna swoop the, swoop the boss.
The dingle gets shooped and swooped.
Uh, oh, wait, I thought it was space.
Why does it work?
It's not working!
Is it missing space?
Oh, that was working.
Ow!
Whoa.
I'm dying here.
It's over.
Don't you whistle at me!
Oh, man.
Binky.
Tear us up, that's good, though.
We need healing real bad.
I do wonder why we transformed to the horror.
Maybe it is because we are at 1 HP.
If I get more HP, hold on, let's check.
Ah, but I can't reach that!
Dang.
Down we go.
So the next one has a timer on it.
I'm eating candy, and I'm puking.
That's very relatable.
Except, maybe not puking, just feeling terrible afterwards, you know?
I could swoop the, swoop here, maybe?
No, I can't, because... reasons.
You need two charges, so why even display two charges?
I don't understand the system.
He's stuck in a corner!
Wow!
Uh-oh, uh-oh.
Kill this guy.
Get him out of here!
Don't you poop.
I hate when they poop.
Speed up.
That means this is speed 2.
No, that's a different blue one.
Yeah!
Amazing!
Secrets, baby!
It's a baby bottle.
Tropicamide, tier size, and something.
Wait, what is it, actually?
Increased tier size, more range.
Ooh, that's good!
Increased size of the tier stats, as well.
It's kind of crazy.
I don't even know what I'm fighting here, I'm just sort of going for it.
It's some kind of bomb, dude, though.
This guy loves his bombs.
Ow!
Yo, this guy's crazy!
Alright, he shoots that little weird ball.
Oh, I can shoot the ball!
Hey, okay.
Oh, what the...
Was I too slow, and now I get another boss?
That what's happening here?
Oh, man.
Oh, he's angry now.
He's going to do the thing.
Oh, wow!
When are you doing it?
Okay, okay, you're doing that now.
I'm so scared of the laser.
Don't laser me.
That was the corner!
Literally couldn't do anything.
Literally was just dead.
I died to a sperm person.
Look at that.
What is that even?
That doesn't even look anything like the guy I died to.
The guy I died to was mean.
Look at his eyes and his teeth.
He was way meaner than that guy.
Makes it seem like I died to a little baby or something.
I didn't.
I died to a crazy enemy.
Oh, my God.
Azazel is just too good.
Um, so the Whore of Babylon...
I want to try Cain.
He's in the spotlight.
Okay, Cain, what do you got?
You only got one eye.
Are you a pirate?
Jesus.
He must have a trick up his sleeve, though.
There was something about...
Oh, man, man!
No!
Wow.
I feel like every character just feels so bad compared to Azazel.
Sad bombs.
Tear blasts plus five bombs.
Tear blasts?
Bombs fire ten shots outward when exploding.
Let
me try that.
Big tears, too.
Very cool.
All right, guys.
Enjoy!
Oh, no way!
Best bomb ever.
Uh-oh.
Uh, yeah, I'm not gonna...
Oh, wait, I have an idea.
Watch this now!
Oh, no, I can't push TNT!
Never mind, then.
I thought I was being super smart.
I wanted to push the TNT up there.
It is what it is.
Clean.
The Emperor.
Teleports to the boss room?
Challenge me.
There's also a secret room in there, but I already found that, so that's fine.
Ow!
Man, this game is difficult.
I'll say that.
This is a hard-ass game.
It seems simple, right?
But, nope.
This game is definitely...
It's difficult.
I didn't mean to enter!
Anyway, here we go.
Gurglings.
Ah, whatever.
In fact, have some bombs.
Enjoy my bombs!
I didn't...
The bombs literally hit nothing.
Oh, my God.
Let's go for...
I mean, I'm going for a record here, guys.
I'm trying to go for 20 losses in a row.
I'm working my way towards it, so I'm actually winning when it comes to my goal.
Guys, we're going Azazel.
It's just the best.
There's no other character that matters.
Watch me just own everything now.
Azazel... unstoppable.
I'm telling you.
You'll see.
Oh, look at that.
Goodness.
Oh, it's beautiful.
We wait until there are lines.
Look at all that poop, though.
Nice.
Now, I'm sure the other characters can be pretty good, too.
I've just had some good success with Azazel, you know?
Azazel is my guy.
Love him.
Just kill him quick before they...
Yeah, exactly.
Wait, how come the others died?
Did they run into the fire?
No way.
They killed themselves.
Metal plate, it itches.
Nice, a soul heart.
25% chance to reflect enemy projectiles as a concussive shot.
Huge!
Really good.
Boomerang?
Shots come back?
That sounds really good, if that's the case.
But how would that work with...
Ah, well, I'm assuming how something works before I even tried it, so let's not go crazy right now.
How would you even do this room?
Ah, I guess you could destroy this if you were Isaac.
Yeah.
I've been unlucky with the fires, though.
Why is this game so...
fun?
Like, it's so simple, but I...
I just, every time I die, I'm like, okay, fuck it.
Let's go again.
Immediately.
I just want to keep going.
Oh my god, these guys are crazy!
Literally impossible to beat them.
Fuck me!
Drive by.
The drive by is the way.
Drive by shooting with Uzis and Teknines.
Oh, look at this rock!
See that?
Amazing gameplay.
Kill that... Oh, I'm not gonna step on that green stuff.
You think I was born yesterday?
Bad trip!
That's actually unbelievable.
That was just straight up unlucky.
Time for the boss!
Ah, the Duke of Flies is easy.
One of my favorite bosses to fight against.
Just get those flies out of the way!
And there we go.
Taken care of.
Can't heal.
What was that?
Oh, that's good.
That's good.
Damage and range up.
I had this before.
The buffs from this item apply only to shots fired from the right eye.
So I'm assuming this is the right eye here, right?
Is it?
Maybe.
Not entirely sure, actually.
Because left eye last time was the laser, right?
Man, this game is just a torture of Isaac, isn't it?
That's what the game name should be.
Whoa.
Dude, that movement was crazy.
They had bombs embedded in their heads!
Thank you, Sharon.
Man, the drive-by method.
Where you just swoop and sweep, you know?
It's so good.
I'm not gonna enter that.
Drive-by... boom!
Oh, I missed.
Oh my god, I can't hit it.
Absolutely no spiders.
I say no to that.
I am locked in right now, actually.
I just realized I'm not even paying attention to anything what's happening.
I'm just sort of feeling it.
It's like I'm plucked in directly to my brain and I'm just sort of feeling the pixels.
It's hard to explain.
I'm not seeing pixels anymore, you know?
I'm just seeing red dress, blue dress, all of that.
Go.
It's like I'm playing the game with peripheral vision.
What's that?
Round cap, far tomb.
Huh?
Poop explodes when destroyed and deals 100 damage!
I don't know if I want that.
That sounds like it could go wrong really fast.
Can I drop items?
Somehow?
I'm actually kind of in trouble.
I have low HP.
Oh no, I'm low on HP here.
Yikes!
We gotta go somewhere else first.
This song is really good.
Nice.
It's over!
It's over.
Oh my god, bruh.
I messed it up bad.
User error, I admit it.
Horrible, horrible.
I called it.
I knew it was gonna go bad.
Okay, again.
It's fine.
We're back.
We're back with more Isaac.
Azazel.
Fuck Isaac.
Azazel is the man.
I was the one who messed it up.
Azazel did fine.
It was me.
I was the one who caused the catastrophe.
May you find all you have lost?
Secret room, baby!
Do it!
This guy wants keys?
No?
He's not getting it.
The fool.
Okay, here we go, here we go.
These guys are gonna explode.
Or I guess spawn bombs.
The mystery gift has appeared.
Okay, so I think what that means now...
Because it's not actually gonna appear in my basement.
It's just like unlocked now.
Now I can see it, you know what I mean?
Oh god.
So that's what that means every time.
Because I have not seen any of those things every time they pop up, right?
Okay.
I just don't know what is triggering it.
I guess it's just maybe amount of enemies killed.
Or something like that.
Amount of stages cleared, you know?
Random stuff like that.
Oh, look at me going in close.
Because I know their patterns.
Gamer.
Oh, poop does not explode anymore.
So I can safely, you know, frolic in it.
I have...
Sanctuary...
No!
That was such a waste.
Didn't need to happen, but it did.
Yeah, I can't destroy that, unfortunately.
I need a bomb.
Pools.
We're gonna wait until he jumps.
Now, go.
That way he can't jump again.
I guess there's a cooldown on it.
No bombs?
Oh, they just explode, okay.
Why did they explode instead of spawning bombs?
Ah, you know what, maybe they did spawn bombs, and I destroyed it with the laser immediately after.
Oh, god!
These guys are gonna explode?
Yeah.
The chariots.
I mean, nothing stands before you.
For six seconds become invisible!
Brother man.
I feel like that's really good if you know when to use it.
I'm not gonna know when it's a good time to use it.
Like, uh...
As soon as I realize things are bad, it's already too late, you know?
That's the problem with that.
Oh, we got a blue dude.
Kayla!
Nice.
Ooh!
Something opened!
What opened?
We need to understand this.
This seems like a big deal.
Also, my key icon on the left is now turned into a golden key.
Oh, shit.
Kay.
Uh-oh, that's an evil fire!
It almost had me there.
What's this?
Blood bombs.
Bloody blast plus HP up!
That's good!
Heels four red hearts.
Wow.
Bomb explosions spawn a puddle of damaging red creep.
Allows placing bombs when bomb count is at zero at the cost of half a heart from Isaac's health meter per bomb.
What an interesting item!
That sounds really cool.
But the best thing there was definitely getting one more HP.
Yeah.
Time for the boss.
We're going boss.
This is the run, guys.
I can feel it.
It's going exceptionally well.
And the music is banging.
How can we lose?
I say we can't.
The blight is over?
Is that like a medical term for something inside the body?
Yo!
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
It hurts.
Man, this guy is fast.
Oh, I can't damage the small guy.
Okay.
I see, I see.
Ah-ha, okay.
Uh, range?
Oh, that's so good.
Wait, does it even affect me?
Hmm, I can't quite tell.
Let's go.
Okay, there's a timer on this one.
Let's try and go fast.
I feel like we can get a reward if we're super fast.
Oh, God.
These cannot explode on me.
Nice.
Kill the flies.
Easy, go.
Speed, speed, speed.
Ah!
He beep, boop that!
Boop!
Oh, my God!
Fuck!
I'm so bad!
Oh, I didn't mean to...
Okay, I'm here now.
I didn't mean to do that.
I can't believe I messed up that room so bad.
That was absolutely despicable.
Oh, no.
Come on.
I killed the sacks.
Nasty stuff.
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
I'm weirdly locked in again now.
It's like I transitioned just now.
I'm not seeing pixels anymore.
It's hard to explain how that works.
It's like I get a tinkle in the tummy, and then it's there.
Oh, oh, wait.
Okay, it's not gonna explode.
It's fine.
Boss, go!
We're on a timer!
Widow!
New boss.
No, we've seen that before.
But it's a crazy boss.
Just damage the bejesus out of the...
You like that?
Bet you hate that.
Oh, you didn't like that, did you, nah?
So that...
So did we get anything?
Eyedrops, tears up.
Oh, that's probably gonna make my charge faster.
Yeah.
Has to be that.
Uh, wait.
We're missing a bunch of rooms down here.
We gotta change that.
Not here, not here.
Oh, god.
Yup, it's a daisy!
I'm in trouble.
These guys are actually so hard.
When you don't have good range, man, that's tough.
Uh, this way.
This room.
Ooh.
Rocket in a jar.
Rocket propulsion?
Hello?
Placing a bomb while holding an attack button will instead launch the bomb as a rocket in that direction.
To place a normal stationary bomb, place it while pressing no attack buttons.
Ha!
That's awesome.
Hey, guys!
Enjoy that, motherfuckers!
You know what?
Yes.
I hate these guys.
He almost hit me.
It's insane.
Ha!
Nice.
Okay, this way.
Oh, crap cake.
Use the terrain.
Play smart.
Use the brain.
Throw the dart.
I'm insane.
Okay, this way.
On here.
Ooh, we can fly!
But are we consistent?
We're consistent.
Love the consistency right now, until it's not consistent.
Uh, secret!
Shit!
Wait, okay, last time I took damage here.
I'm not gonna... nope.
I'm not gonna risk it.
Ooh!
Why are there empty rooms, though, if it's not a secret?
I'm confused.
It's time to leave.
We're done here.
The chariot, what was that?
Oh, yeah, the insane, invincible thing.
Yeah, that sounds really good.
And we have to remember, that is on cue, not space.
Okay, stage...
Oh, we got a timer thing again!
Speed!
Engage!
Nitrous oxide.
Boom!
Grab the chest.
Grab the chicken.
Squeeze the tears up.
Squeeze my tears.
What is that?
How's that not a chicken?
Two soul hearts?
That's huge!
Mega!
Kill everything?
Lovely!
Go!
And we got pamos.
Oh, shit.
Oh, this is actually getting a little risky!
How come you're not dying?
Okay, you're dead.
Huge!
Go!
Bomberman!
I'm chilling against this guy as Azazel.
Wow.
He has no chance against me!
Thanks!
Bye-bye.
Where's the boss?
Here?
Okay.
Nice.
We killed these first.
And then we killed the small ones.
Lovely.
Uh, this is a fight room.
I'm taking it all.
Take it all!
Pill me!
Pill!
Shit!
That's bad.
That's good!
Ooh!
Not bad at all!
We're chilling!
Oh, look at me dodging!
I'm a pro!
Holy crap!
Unstoppable, man!
Tomatoes!
Oh, no, I got hit.
Okay, so it's diagonally.
So I'm safe when I'm straight.
Okay, good.
Up.
Speed, speed, speed, speed.
There's a timer on it, or something.
I don't know what's happening with the timer, but it's here!
Chest me!
Pill!
Log up!
That's good!
Go!
No!
Back!
Oh, shit!
I needed the invisibility thing.
Uh, we're safe.
What's that?
Red patch?
Your rage grows?
Uh...
It's the thing in the bottom left.
20% chance to gain damage off of the curtain room each time you take damage?
That's crazy.
I need this thing over here.
Hang a shirt.
A chariot will totally just roll through here.
Uh, come on!
Oh, nice!
Oh, no!
It ran out right when I did it!
That's unlucky.
Come on, dude!
Thanks.
Kill him fast!
Got him.
Strength, may your power bring rage.
Uh...
For the curtain room plus one...
Wow, really?
Oh, just for the curtain room, okay.
Oh, god.
Oh, no.
Oh!
I took damage!
Boss!
Monstro, it's double trouble time.
Whoa.
Uh, this is bad.
I'm totally dead here!
Yeah!
Oh,
my god!
This is impossible.
Jesus.
Okay, you're gonna jump now?
You're not jumping?
Oh!
What is down?
What is this?
Get him!
I can't believe we defeated that!
Glass eye!
That's good!
It's really good.
Okay, um...
We go back.
Man, I really want to try and understand what this timing thing means.
Did I just get minus a bunch of stuff?
What happened?
Oh, maybe it was the active I activated.
It did something.
Thank you.
I got 11 coins.
These guys are so difficult to deal with, the flying heads thingies.
I really think they're so hard.
Oh, that's a nice room right there.
That is a fart pillow.
Vascularitis.
Clocked enemies.
Enemies launch shots in random directions on death.
Enemies with bigger health pools launch more shots.
I'm hoping these shots are on my side.
Shots inherit ISX tier effects and damage other enemies.
Woah!
So that means it's going to be a laser or what?
Hold the phone.
That sounds really good.
Oh no.
It doesn't work.
It's not a laser.
What a scam.
Unbelievable.
Uh, do we get a vacuum cleaner?
We can afford it.
Mom's bottle of pills.
Oh, okay.
Uh, space.
Experimental pill, tears up, locked down.
That's... I like it.
I like it.
Now we need more mana.
I like this one.
Uh, time to get out.
We're done here.
Next level.
There we go.
Was there anything else in this room?
Nah.
That was a crazy boss.
Two of them.
We got a timer again.
Okay, we got to go fast.
This time.
This time we're going to go super quick.
Please just die.
Oh, man.
Good.
Destroy the poop.
And go.
Man, I'm going to think those projectiles are bad for me, but they're not.
They're good for me.
They're my projectiles.
Wait, did we just break the door or what happened there?
Uh, what's happening here?
Bomb it.
Wow!
Liberty cap!
Touch fuzzy, get dizzy!
We just get that?
25% chance to gain a random passive mushroom effect for the room.
Sick!
But do I want that instead of this?
Oh, I didn't even update yet.
There we go.
20% chance to gain damage up for the current room.
Uh...
I mean, ideally, I don't want to take damage, right?
So I think I want this more.
Nice.
Eight.
This way.
We're on a timer here.
Uchibrapa!
Yeah!
Kill him.
Wait, that was a bad one.
Wait for him.
See ya in hell.
It was a spike in chest!
That's super unfair.
There were no spikes on it when I looked at it.
No, not the tick!
Cheers up, speed down.
That's fine.
I hate the damn tick.
We gotta do drive-bys on these guys.
It's the only way.
Yeah, I have figured these guys out.
It's the drive-by method.
That's how you deal with them.
Nothing.
Nice.
Whoa!
What is that?
Not sure what that is.
We're going for it.
Polyphallus!
That's a new boss.
Okay, I see you there, I see you there.
Killing the ads here?
Oh god.
Oh no!
Wow, okay, we gotta go in a round in a circle, I see.
Oh man.
I can't believe we won.
Growth hormones, speed and damage up.
That is really good.
Two damage?
Isn't that massive?
Go back.
I still have things to explore.
I'm so sad, I lost my mushroom.
Oh, this one was...
No, I hate that one, I don't like that at all.
What?
Oh man, we need a couple more coins.
We can surely get that.
I wanna try that thing.
Go this way.
Oh god, this is gonna be really hard!
We can't really drive by here.
Fuck, how are you supposed to do that?
Without getting hit.
That is evil.
Okay, oh no.
Wow.
Man, this game is just...
My heart rate is always in the 150.
Okay, so this door just opened.
Why?
Meat!
Good.
Oh wow, we just got a boss like that, just like that!
Jesus.
Oh no!
See ya!
Oh, you're not dead, you're not dead.
What a room though.
Oh, what is that?
It's a demon!
Nice try, brother.
Not good enough.
Holy shit.
I can't believe that.
That is crazy.
ROID RAGE.
Little baggy has appeared.
I don't know what that is, but it sounds like a good thing.
I like little bags.
Dude, I'm super fast, look at this!
Oh, have I ever been this fast before?
I don't know.
That's a drive-by.
Ah, you bastard.
I'm not gonna give you anything.
Nope, absolutely not.
Did I just play as a bomb?
Accidentally?
Envy!
Oh my god.
The Book of Sin!
Has appeared.
Sure, whatever.
This is addicting as hell.
It's crazy.
I need some HP here.
There is a half a heart in the last room.
We can get that.
Wait!
The bomb I placed ten minutes ago!
Look!
That's funny, so that just stays there and...
explodes again when it's time I come back, huh?
Gimme that.
Alright, let's go.
It's a candy.
But it's bad for you.
Depths one.
I'm in the depths!
I hate when enemies do that.
It makes me really anxious.
I don't know what that is, but it needs to die.
There are so many different enemies.
I feel like I see new enemies every single run I do.
Insanity.
Brainiacs.
What if that's their actual name?
What a chest.
Now I want a shop room.
Ho ho ho!
Damn, son.
Uh oh.
Monsters!
Just like that?
Isn't that kinda crazy?
Oh god.
Loki, I'm killing it.
I don't know what that means.
Maybe that actually turns you into a flying creature when you're not flying before.
It doesn't really say what it does.
Wait, are these gonna activate or something?
You motherfucker!
Oh, what?!
Yeah, no, no.
See you later, dude.
Absolutely not.
That is just rude as hell.
Uh oh.
Guys, we're dead here.
I don't even know what we're facing!
It's over!
Maybe.
It's not over.
We're back, maybe.
But maybe we're dead again.
We're probably dead here.
You're pooping.
Stop pooping.
I don't like it when you poop.
Please die.
Thank the lord.
Range.
Oh, that's fantastic.
I like range.
That's a good range now.
What is this?
What do we got?
Why are there so many bosses in this place?
You're like, every room has been a boss almost.
Oh no, not you.
I'm gonna blow your shit up.
Your shit has now been blown up.
But you take coins, huh?
Okay, fine.
I'll give you three.
Okay, you die now.
I get him back!
I took damage.
Oh, the rocks!
Oh no, the spiky rocks.
That's how I took damage.
Oh man.
Give me something good.
What is that?
Jump?
How to jump?
It's time you learned how.
Alright.
I said jumps in the direction he's currently moving can be used to jump over gaps, enemies, and...
Oh, that's kind of bad though.
Because I can fly.
Why would I jump?
So there is actually a way for Isaac to jump in the game.
That's what I was wondering from day one, you know?
Which is last time.
It's been two days so far.
Whoa, wow.
Okay, okay.
There's pee everywhere and poop as well.
So much poop and pee.
Uh-oh.
Oh, they're shooting things!
He's alternating.
Okay.
Got him.
Easy.
The baby bottle is doing wonders.
Okay.
Should we gamble?
Hey!
What if I blow it up?
What's that?
Oh, it's the tick blocking and it's some kind of item.
Man, oh man.
I could have had something there.
Oh god, oh god, get out of there.
Wow.
Kimi.
Spiders.
Uh, the blue are good for me, right?
No, they're not.
They're bad.
Oh, thank god we got healing.
We're back!
Uh, this was the...
Ventricle Racer.
Two-link tunnel.
Oh, actually...
What was the one I currently have?
Oh, you know what?
I'd rather have this.
That's good.
I like being infested.
Dude, I think I'm gonna take this to 100.
Something's gonna happen now.
Store upgrade!
Yeah!
Okay, okay.
I wonder what that means.
Better items?
More items?
Cheaper items?
I say yes please to all of that.
It's time for the boss though.
Oh man, this room is crazy.
Whoa, the gate!
Whoa!
What are you doing?
You're spawning little guys?
Got it.
That's fine.
Whoa!
Not too bad, it seems.
We got him.
Okay, that wasn't too bad at all.
Mom's coin purse.
More pills?
Oh, experimental is good for me.
Fuck my luck.
Amnesia.
Wait, what is that?
What did I just get?
What did it do?
Bomb's your key.
No!
That's bad.
Oh, look at this!
We got a Pope hat!
Mitre, blessing of purity.
Seraphim.
33% chance of converting red heart drops into soul hearts.
Soul hearts are the black ones, right?
Wait, curse of the lost.
What does that mean?
Why does it say curse of the lost?
There's a question mark, purple question mark in the top right.
Huh?
Oh, wait, I'm... No, I'm lost now!
How did I get that?
What gave me that?
Oh, was it a random pill?
I think it was a random pill.
Shit.
Pills are bad.
Jump in the cellar.
And die.
Wow.
Okay, straight up.
Just jump through a hole and die.
Oh, look at our character though!
Wow.
That is some luck.
Damn.
I like.
Okay.
Alright.
Let me get ready with some attacks here.
Okay.
Oh, I owned them.
And now I get something, right?
Right?
That's crazy.
Unless I need to activate all buttons at the same time and then defeat enemies, that's the only way I get a chest.
Or something like that, there's a chest icon, right?
I can see that being a thing.
Wow.
That... lemon part.
That's a lot of pee.
That's a special shit.
Man.
That was rough.
Wait, uh...
Let me blow it up.
Dude, I can gamble a little bit, blow it up, and then maybe get money back?
There was already some money in there.
What's this room?
There's a piece of paper here.
Oh.
A piece of meat.
Dude, it's going really well.
Come on out, come on out.
Lovely.
I can pre-charge before going inside rooms.
Oh, God!
Keep moving.
Uh, you want bombs, huh?
You want keys.
Huh.
You know what?
Why not?
Have one.
Again.
Oh!
Huge!
Hey!
No way!
No, no!
I didn't mean to do that.
Okay, you know what?
Ah!
The...
I gotta do this.
Why can't I...
Okay, there we go.
It's free, it's free, so now I go here and I do this.
Why aren't the chests moving?
I'm losing my mind.
Oh, God.
Okay, now it moved.
Pretty fly.
Why not?
Uh, a bomb for you?
Hell yeah.
Have some more.
Ah.
Remote detonator.
Cool.
Plus five bombs.
Detonates all place the bombs.
Oh!
While held, bombs do not detonate on an automatic timer.
That is kind of cool.
I dig it.
Oh!
They can actually kill themselves.
Or kill each other.
Oh!
Oh, I've had this one before.
Okay, so Soulheart is the black one, right?
25% chance to reflect enemy.
Okay, Soul is blue.
Okay.
Got it.
So the other heart that I read about earlier was the black one, I guess.
Okay.
Uh, we got a shop here and we have money.
Boomerang, we gotta try it.
The Boomerang, it will never leave you.
There was a Boomerang that hits for two times Isaac's damage, petrifies enemies and can collect pickups.
That sounds pretty cool actually, but...
Wait, if I pick this up again, am I gonna get another five bombs?
Ah, too bad, huh?
Too bad.
This one is speed down, yeah.
Let's not spend money to get that.
Sounds absolutely horrible.
So wait, let me see this Boomerang again.
Two times Isaac's damage, okay.
Wait, I'm gonna try and blow this one up.
There's a pill.
What does that mean?
Did we grow some hairs on our schlong or what?
I didn't mean to do that.
Oh well.
Hey!
Sick?
I'm gonna blow everything up from now on.
This is the new standard.
Uh-oh.
Drive-by.
Love the drive-by.
Ooh, that's the boss.
I'm not going yet.
I got a room over here that needs to investigate.
Blow him up!
Nice.
And now we go.
Here we go!
Oh, it's Mom!
Here we go.
Right, right.
Oi, yi, yi!
Yeah, you're done!
You're done.
Tears up.
Tears up, baby, tears up.
Now, am I gonna go in here?
No, because they're gonna want me to leave some health to get some items.
And you know what?
I say no to that.
I reject.
The poop fell out of her ass.
So now we're gonna be in the uterus.
No?
Woom!
Oh my goodness.
So wait, we're not even born yet?
I hope she's not drinking right now.
I hope she's not smoking.
That's all I'm saying.
Mom, don't do it.
Follow the rules.
Okay, okay.
Going well so far.
What's that?
A hermit.
Oh, that's gonna take me to the shop.
Huh?
I should have read it.
I was so sure as well, but okay.
I guess I was wrong.
There we go.
A black heart for me.
Yeah, baby.
Is that poop or pee?
Okay, it's probably neither.
Looks like some kind of stomach acid.
Yeah, that's probably what that is.
I don't know what that is, but we kill it.
Dude, I'm speedrunning the game right now.
I don't even know what's happening and I'm winning.
Kill it all.
Okay, down here.
Oh, I like this effect on this level.
Okay, let's go here.
Okay.
Wait, what?
Oh, there's a button.
I see.
There's no way I can dodge this.
I can't do it.
I'm too dumb.
Wait, this is actually safe.
Yeah, that one's safe.
Holy shit.
What?
Okay, so wait, we can...
Save spot is here.
Holy shit!
Actually, gamer.
Down here.
Enjoy.
I don't even know what I'm dealing with here.
I'm kind of sucker.
Ohoy!
Laser beams!
Huh?
Oh!
All right, all right, all right.
I see how it is.
You're dead, though.
Yeah.
I'm getting judgment.
Judged.
That gives me a beggar.
That's one of those that sits down and wants coins.
Should I give him coins?
Since I spawned him, maybe he has a higher chance of being good to me.
Huh?
Yeah, that's not worth it.
But I'm going to blow him up.
I'm going to blow him up.
Okay, I'm going to blow him up now.
He only gave me one?
Okay, I thought I would get everything back.
Maybe that's a bit broken if that was the case.
Jesus!
All right, I guess my black heart just took care of business.
There's also room for that.
Okay, yeah, this is going to be a bit weird.
Man, I love that I can charge so fast.
Oh, super magnet.
Slowly pulls all pickups and all enemies toward Isaac.
And enemies, too?
Yeah, no thanks.
Pride!
You ain't got nothing on me, brother.
I'm going to fuck you up.
Okay.
So what are these?
Oh, they shoot lasers.
Okay, I see.
Ah, you bastard.
I'm not falling for that.
Have a bomb instead.
He actually stole a coin from me.
A little rascal.
Wait, wait, wait.
That was a room.
Okay, not bad.
The chariot.
That one's good.
It's the one that gives me protection.
Wait, there's more down here.
I keep going away.
Nice.
Man, the womb is not too shabby so far.
I enjoy the womb.
I'm getting better at dodging the shots.
Can't let the tomatoes grow.
Oh, there's a boss.
I didn't mean to.
Loki!
There's two of them.
Oh, there are two halves.
No way.
We got him.
Mr. Dolly, that's a good one.
And a black heart, too.
Now, there's a room I didn't explore.
I'm gonna go back.
Nice.
Lock up.
That's good.
Okay, so I think what happens with the...
I think what's going on with the pills is that every single sort of run that you're on, the colors are randomized.
But once you find them, you know what they are, right?
Because otherwise, you would see... I would have gotten them all by now, pretty much.
So that's what's happening here.
That's nice.
Now I know what is luck and what is bad and all that stuff.
Oh, yeah.
Did we jump further down?
Where are we gonna end up next in her rectum?
Utero 2!
Oh, my.
Okay, then.
Hey.
Infested?
That's good, though.
That means we get a spider.
Yeah.
This one is the chariot.
That's good.
Very nice room there.
Very nice.
I mean, sure.
Two bomber men!
Luckily, Azazel is pretty OP against the bomber men.
Okay.
I still have yet to try the chariot.
Oh, he teleported.
He charges me.
Oh, just keep charging, okay.
So they don't stop unless they hit something.
Get to know.
That door is closed.
Oh, okay, so I gotta kill these guys, whatever they are.
Oh, they spawn flies?
Yo!
Insanity!
What a room!
Absolutely nuts!
Holy crap.
These guys are scary.
Okay, they're not laser guys.
That's good.
Actually, when they're not laser, it's not too bad.
I gotta dry fight these so bad.
How do I dodge that?
I'm losing all of my HP here.
Oh, it's bad.
And this guy wants coins again, this greedy bastard.
Do I give him?
I'm gonna give him.
Come on, man.
Puke up the best thing ever.
What if, okay.
Let's say I give him a million coins, and then I blow him up.
Maybe there's a super high chance he gives me something incredible, then.
Another chariot?
Brother, man.
Ahh, I'm using all my money.
Okay, fuck it.
Kill him.
Line him up!
Oh, dude, look at this.
We're gonna go like this.
We're gonna grab everyone.
Everyone, follow me.
And then we line him up.
Okay, that wasn't too impressive there, but you get the idea.
Uh-huh.
What a weird room.
There's nothing in here.
Except the hearts.
The boss.
Oh, I hear...
I hear the boss.
Behind the door.
Wow, that went really well.
I freakin' handled that room.
Oh, they come back, right.
Oh!
Just like that, eh?
Oh, you're dead already?
That's good.
Man, I'm kinda killing it.
I'm doing it.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, these guys need to die.
Oh, I hate this!
Activate!
I'm invisible!
I can't attack!
Oh, right, okay, that's kinda shitty then.
I don't like it then.
I hate it.
I guess I could run into him.
Yeah, I should've thought about that.
There is a room in the bottom right there.
Can I access that, or is it still closed off to me?
Let's find out.
Perhaps I did something that made it open.
Nope.
I'm not deserving of the room.
Apparently.
I could use some more health.
This is not enough for me.
Time for the boss.
Mom's heart!
Whoa!
Okay, I killed the ice.
Absolutely yes.
Wow!
I'm still dead.
Kill the small guys!
Here we go!
Oi!
Wow!
Look at that, baby!
Massive chest!
Nice butt!
Wait, what's happening right now?
Was that a bobbed haircut?
Yeah, we owned it!
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
Wait, there's another credits here.
Very nice.
What a run!
Man, I gotta be honest.
These last stages, I didn't even realize what was going on half the time.
I was just like, laser go bzzt!
Laser go bzzt!
And things just die.
I guess I just had the right combo of items and...
Somehow, I managed to dodge all those freaking projectiles at the end.
I don't know how I did that.
When I saw that, I was like, I'm dead.
I'm dead.
There's no way I'm gonna win this.
Somehow, I was locked in, man.
I was in the pixels.
It was crazy.
Ho, ho, ho!
Dude, my heart rate is like all the way up right now.
Ho, ho!
Man.
So now, we have been inside my mom's uterus.
Her, uh, womb.
Twice, I guess.
Once when we, oh, you unlocked Eden.
Begotten baby.
Nice.
New unlocks.
And we got a bunch of new characters, by the way.
I unlocked, like, three or four characters or something.
Guys, that was nuts!
This game is addicting!
It's very fun to play.
I can't stop playing.
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Oh, my God.
You're getting better?
I'm damn right I am.
I owned that just now.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
First heart kill.
Amazing.
Great run and damn fine luck.
I would say so, yeah.
I mean, that's what it is with roguelikes, right?
Sometimes you get lucky with items, sometimes you don't.
But that was just a storm of good things happening in a row.
The planets aligned for this one, for sure.
Made a lot of people pour potatoes.
Oh, my God!
You guys are betting on this stuff!
What were you betting on?
I need to see this.
How can I see the last bets?
Were you just betting on whether or not I did the run or survived the run?
Ha, ha!
What was the percentage like on the people who were betting?
How do I see them?
I started a prediction.
Oh, I can see it here.
Eighty-nine percent of you thought I was going to lose!
Oh, what a payout!
Damn!
Thirty-seven thousand channel points.
I've ordered to nine viewers.
Non-believers, huh?
Using active items as passive items is crazy strategy.
The thing is, I'm barely just trying to focus on what's happening on the screen with all these new enemies and all these new areas.
I can't be thinking about clicking no buttons.
Come on now.
One day I'll learn, okay?
Oh, to scroll in my things menu, press tab.
Thank you, fizzy man.
Huge!
I totally forgot to ask you, so thanks for reminding me.
Yes, I needed to know that.
Appreciate it.
So that's how you do that.
I was losing my mind over that.
I mean, you can put it in the promotions or in the clip channel on the Discord if you want, false boy.
That's what a lot of people do.
Did you notice that the mom's hands that fall on you are like in Zelda?
Actually, I didn't.
But now that you say it, they do look like the floor masters.
I would not have made that connection on my own, though.
That's kind of funny.
Also, when I had that run with the tattle, that was totally like Zelda inspired, too.
Seems like there's a lot of references here to Zelda.
Keep playing on hard.
You're already getting really good at... I mean...
I thought the idea was to, you know, up at the ante every time, so next I'm gonna play on greed.
I guess it's the hardest one.
Don't tell me, of course.
Don't tell me anything.
I'll figure it out.
I also have a bunch of things to do, all these characters I gotta try on, and all these challenges and shit.
Man.
What is ISTG?
Yeah, no spoilers, please.
I mean, you can tell me you love me, Eicher.
That's fine.
I love you, too.
We all love each other here.
There's only love here on this channel.
Holy... Dude, it's been almost five hours.
This game is sucking time out of me.
Oh!
Oh, I swear to God, right, of course.
I knew that one, actually.
I just forgot.
I've seen it before.
Maybe we'll get one million subs sooner with facecam?
Yeah, maybe.
Probably.
But I don't need to right now.
I'm chilling.
I like the status quo right now with the channel.
This one is a funny one to watch, as my name is Isaac.
Oh, is it?
Nice.
I'm guessing you have played this game, then.
No cam is fine, yeah.
One day I'll probably do some camera let's plays, or facecam let's plays.
Because I think some games are more attuned to that.
You know, games that have maybe less gameplay?
More story elements and more voiceovers and acting and all that?
I think that's more fun to see a facecam.
Because, I mean, I can't really talk over what's happening in the game in those instances, right?
So maybe, at least you can see my face.
So some games lend themselves better to that sort of stuff.
I love your vids, but how do you avoid spoilers in the comments?
I honestly just have a sixth sense with it.
It's hard to explain.
When I read through the comments, it's easy to see from a mile away when someone is spoiling.
But sometimes I also choose not even to read comments.
Like, lately I haven't been reading too many Silksong comments, for example.
Because it's gotten really bad.
With that, so I just don't even read those.
I've not actually gone through blueprints and red comments.
I wanted to, but I was on the fence whether or not I was going to continue or not, so I didn't really wanted to do it yet, so...
Because once I do it, you know, it spoils forever, so to speak.
So it's a weird limbo that I find myself in, regarding that.
Apparently there's also an update coming for blueprints, right?
Maybe that would be an opportunity to jump back in or something.
I look for every Parlor-related comment and put them at the end of my...
Yeah, or maybe make it so that, like, when you show something on screen from the Let's Play...
On the related video, on top, when that scene is happening, you know what I mean?
So it's, like, related in time.
Oh my god, I'm so bad at expressing myself.
But, like, have the comments on screen that are relevant at the time when it's happening, you know what I mean?
That would be cool.
Not that related, but one more run... Dude, if I do one more run, it's going to turn into ten more runs.
And I need to eat now, and Jackie needs to eat.
I need to take care of myself.
Haha.
I kind of love these games where you want to do one more, and one more, and one more.
Please, ten more runs, then.
Nah, okay, we'll do ten more runs.
I'm kidding.
Next ice extreme went probably very soonish, because I'm kind of addicted to this right now.
Like, this is actually, like, straight into my veins.
I need more.
Especially now that I've, you know, gotten blood on my teeth.
And I can feel myself getting better.
Oh, man.
I'm not going to say that, you know, I'm the best, but...
I'm the best.
And that's going to, you know, get me... keep me going, at least.
For the foreseeable future, this way it's going to fuel me for a while.
Digital crack, exactly.
Yeah, that's a good way of describing it.
All right, guys, I'm going to be out of here.
Thank you, everyone, for subscribing.
I see all the subscribers.
There's so many.
I can't even, like...
Thank you so much for all the support.
It's crazy.
You guys are enjoying the ice extremes here.
I can tell.
So am I.
The perfect symbiosis.
I wish you a happy Tuesday.
Thanks for checking out this stream.
Subscribing, following, and just hanging out and chatting.
It means the world.
You guys are the best.
I'll see you next time.